Sunny: Please confirm in the chat?
Sunny: So let's begin with the session.
Sunny: Please confirm in the chat API code.
Sunny: Hello, everyone. I'm audible, guys. Can you please hear, can you please confirm in the chat?
Sunny: If you're able to hear me, then…
Sunny: Okay, great. So let's begin with the class, let's begin with the session.
Sunny: So, just, give me a moment, guys. Wait.
Sunny: Yeah, now my voice is perfect.
Sunny: Okay, fine, guys.
Sunny: So, let's, let's start with the session, guys, let's start with the class.
Sunny: Off… Wait.
Sunny: I hope I'm visible, too.
Sunny: Everyone is able to see me, everyone is able to hear me.
Sunny: Yup.
Sunny: Yeah, great.
Sunny: So, thank you guys, thank you, first of all, for your, wishes. So, yeah.
Sunny: Thank you very much. Thank you, Shiva. Thank you, Abhijit. Thank you, Praval.
Sunny: Thank you, Abhik. Thank you very much.
Sunny: Yeah, rajesh, Praveen… Privatra, Raghur… So, thank you guys, thank you for your best wishes, yeah.
Sunny: Someone is saying, happy birthday. No, it's not my birthday.
Sunny: Today is Teacher's Day, right? So, that's why everyone is wish… wishing, everyone is writing.
Sunny: See, I think many of you don't know, right? So, we are celebrating Teacher's Day in India, right? So, 5th of September, right? In memory of Saravilli Radha Krishna.
Sunny: So, when we were in our school and in our colleges, actually, so we used to celebrate, this,
Sunny: Teacher's Day. So, how many of you, like, you remember your school days,
Sunny: Maybe after your half day or the full day, basically, the celebration was going on, and the teachers and all, everyone was giving the speeches, and even we were appreciating the teachers.
Sunny: Even though we don't, we didn't, like, like those teachers, but still, we were saying, okay, this teacher is our favorite teacher, that teacher is our favorite teacher, something like this, right?
Sunny: Yeah, I remember, basically, in my school days, no? So, after half day, so we used to sit in queues, and then our principal was giving the, this speech and all, then the teachers was coming, then the students were coming, something like that.
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: Okay, great guys, so…
Sunny: Yeah, even we used to give the gifts, to the teachers, actually. So, the one and very, one and very favorite gift, actually, right? So, every, every student gives their same gift to the teacher, that is pen, right? So, we, we used to give that pen to the teacher.
Sunny: Okay, great.
Sunny: Fine, so guys, let's start with the session. So, in the previous class, first of all, let me open my dashboard.
Sunny: Just a second.
Sunny: Yeah, this is our dashboard, and
Sunny: I think the UI interface has been changed.
Sunny: So guys, here itself, you'll find out all the sessions.
Sunny: I think left-hand side, you will find out all the sessions.
Sunny: Are you able to see the same kind of UI? It is for everyone, or it is for the admin one? Let me check it out once.
Sunny: Okay, you are seeing the old UI. Okay, fine. So, guys, actually, we were talking about the
Sunny: Langraph, right?
Sunny: So, in the previous, class, basically, I discussed, the tool calling flow, right? I discuss the tool calling flow, how, basically, we can do the orchestration inside the Langraph, all those things we have already covered. Now, what we will do, we'll understand couple of more concepts of the Langraph, okay?
Sunny: So, I have seen, like, someone was saying, sir, you have not showcased this, you have not showcased that, so I already discussed, those things. Let me highlight a couple of messages over here before proceeding with the session.
Sunny: So, where is your batch, guys? I think this… they have changed the UI, maybe.
Sunny: Some operation is there.
Sunny: Okay, no worries, I'll check that. So, guys, every, kind of session is there over the dashboard itself, and one more thing. See, don't worry, see, someone was saying, sir, you're not giving the real, time example. So, whatever example I have discussed, those are the real-world example only.
Sunny: So whenever you're going to be built something in the industry, you are going to be built around to that only.
Sunny: So don't think that, those examples is not a real world, we cannot utilize that. It's not like that.
Sunny: Those examples is completely real world. From those concepts itself, you are going to be built a solution in the real time.
Sunny: Understood. So whatever code and all I'm giving you now, inside this live class, so please, utilize the same code. Please, basically, use the same code when you are building something.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And when we will do the project, at that time, again, we will discuss a couple of, like, more use cases, and even in the practical also, again, we will look into some end-to-end practical inside the Langraph. After 3 to 4 sessions, I will discuss those one. So again, I will discuss couple of more use cases and all, okay? Getting my point?
Sunny: And then, basically, I will give you the assignment also. So, from there, that assignment also, you can, basically, understand so many things, you can practice on top of it, like you practice inside the RAG assignment. Getting my point?
Sunny: Okay? So, here, guys, you can see the RAG assignment. I already uploaded. I have not uploaded the solution of couple of assignments, but I'm thinking to upload all the solution. I have all the solution with me, so don't worry, guys, inside the same GitHub repository.
Sunny: I will upload those solutions. Got it? Now in the previous class, we were talking about the
Sunny: tool calling. So I've shown you the React agent, tool calling methods, and we understood so many different, different concepts of the tool calling, inside, this Langraph. Okay, if you, if you have not seen this particular session, please go and check.
Sunny: This is very important. Now, guys, in today's class, I will discuss couple of more things, okay? So, first, guys, I will discuss about the pythonic.
Sunny: So, this particular concept is the remaining one, so we'll discuss about the pyntic. After that, guys, what I will do, after the pydentic, basically, we'll discuss about the Langraph memory, right? How you can manage the thread, how you can manage the memory inside the Langraph. I'll discuss those concepts.
Sunny: And then tomorrow, guys, again, one more new concept inside the Langraph, like human and loop.
Sunny: Then, next week, again, we'll see the different, different orchestrator and all, okay? So, these are many concepts we are going to be discussed, right, today and the upcoming session. I hope the idea is clear. So, guys, today is class 43, and today is 5th of September.
Sunny: And here you can see the pythontec.ipYNB. I will update this, sorry, I will, basically, update this IPYNB. Couple of things I've kept over here, but yeah, so many things I'm going to be teaching you inside, this particular session. Related the pythonic, as well as the Langraph Memory. Understood, guys?
Sunny: If the idea and the agenda clear, please let me know in the chat so that I can proceed.
Sunny: So, first of all, let me close all the files from here, and then, guys, what I will do, I will start from scratch. Got it?
Sunny: So, async, I will not discuss in today's session. Async, I will discuss in, other class. So, once, I will teach you some, different workflow inside the Langraph.
Sunny: Like, fan in or fan out, okay? So at that time, I will, show you the asynchronization also. That is not a very, typical or very different concept, right?
Sunny: Sometime we are using, sometime we are not using, so again, it is not a mandatory one, right? If you wanted to achieve the concurrency and all, so we have, like, for the multiprocessing and all.
Sunny: We have some other different way also, but yeah, I will give you the idea of the async also. We'll try to develop some workflow, and we'll use the async methodology over there, okay? Now, and then, guys, I will show you how does it work.
Sunny: And, one more thing, see, in the next class, guys, sorry, next to next class, maybe the next weekend, so we'll discuss the different, different workflow inside the Lang Rav. So, so far, basically, I've shown you, one workflow and then one, tool calling method and all.
Sunny: But yeah, there are so many, different workflows, like synthesizer, okay, fan in, fan out.
Sunny: or reducer, optimizer, send API, subgraph and all. So those concepts also I will discuss in the next weekend.
Sunny: And then, guys, during that, I can discuss about this async and all. I hope this is making sense. So today, what we will focus… so today, guys, we'll focus over the pythonic, and after the pythonic, we'll start from the Langraph memory.
Sunny: Is it clear, guys So, let me rename the folder first.
Sunny: So, here, guys, I'm going to be write the different name of the folder.
Sunny: Leng Gaurav… Memory. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So I hope, this screen is visible. Let me zoom in a little bit so that you can see.
Sunny: 30, I guess, is here, no, this one, tool calling method.
Sunny: Tool calling method and the Agentic with tool calling.
Sunny: So, 29th and 30th of August, it was having the same kind of, it was having the same kind of content.
Sunny: So… Here only I have mentioned. Got it, Sathish? This one?
Sunny: In the website… okay, we'll have to check, got it. I think there is some, like, naming differences, here as well as in the GitHub, right? Sorry, in the website itself.
Sunny: So what I will do, guys, I will update those names according to this GitHub itself. So as of now, you can only follow the GitHub, so I will rename those names. So, whoever is seeing the different name over the dashboard, I will definitely rename those. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So, let me do one thing, let me rename it inside the file explorer itself.
Sunny: Because here it is not able to do that. Just a second.
Sunny: Pyrentic and Langraph Memory. Now it will ask to me to close this one.
Sunny: Then try again, now it's done.
Sunny: So, CMD… And then, code dot.
Sunny: Now, here is what, guys? This is my… folder, okay?
Sunny: Which I opened inside the VS Code.
Sunny: So, can we start? Just give me a quick thumbs up, guys. If everything is fine, then I think we can start. So, what I'm doing, over here, I'm going to create a new file.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, I'm going to be creating a new file. So, the file name is going to be pydentic IPYNB. pydentic dot IPYNB.
Sunny: pythonic, you're going to be used a lot when, basically, you are working in any sort of a project, just for the schema checking, okay? Just, to enforce any schema on any sort of a program, or on any sort of a functionality. So there, the pythontec is being used a lot.
Sunny: So, anyone is having any sort of idea related to the Pyrentic, have you used the pythonc anywhere inside any sort of a project? I think most of you, you are having this idea.
Sunny: Right? Most of you are having this idea.
Sunny: at multiple places, we are going to be used. It is not an AI-specific concept, okay? It is a generic concept only, so in the web development also, while… when we are sending a data from server to client, client to server, right?
Sunny: At that time, what we are doing, we are using this pythontec modeling. Got it, guys? Yes or no? So, for the schema validation, we are using this Pyntic.
Sunny: Now, Pyrentic and Pyrentic AI both are the different thing, right? So don't be confused that Pyrentic is similar to the Pyrentic AI, no. Pyrentic AI, basically, it is a framework for the Agentic AI, and Pyrentic is a pythonic library for the data validation.
Sunny: Getting, this point, yes or no?
Sunny: Tell me?
Sunny: Okay. Now, guys, let me check whether this notebook is working fine or not. So, simply, I can write over here, all OK, and I can check whether this notebook is working fine or not. Now, after that, guys, what I will do, I will
Sunny: basically start, writing a code, right? So, guys, see, I will, explain you from starting, how does it work.
Sunny: And then, guys, after completing this part, what we are going to do, after completing, basically, this part, we are going, to understand the memory concept, right? How this Langraf memory works.
Sunny: Okay. Interview question, I think I already shared the interview question. Guys, you got the interview question, no? Basically, I shared those interview questions inside the GitHub, itself. So if you haven't seen those, please go and check. It will give you the good understanding of the GAI interview, right?
Sunny: Couple of more questions I will update over there, as we'll progress in the course. Maybe after the project, basically, I will update those interview questions.
Sunny: So, guys, let's start, let's start with the python text. So, guys, here, I'm going to be right couple of points. Now, just, let me know if you are comfortable with these particular points, okay? I already kept some point inside my notepad, so I'll just copy and paste thing to explain you this entire one.
Sunny: No, guys, here, what I have written, so I've written the incoming data, then we have the parentic model. Okay, now, why we are going to be create a parentic model? So, we're going to be create this pairedic model for the
Sunny: 4D?
Sunny: required field, okay, for the correct type, for validating the range, for the correct format. So, we are going to be validating these many things, or maybe more than this one, using the model.
Sunny: If our validation is passed, then guys, we are continuing. If our validation is fail, then we are…
Sunny: So, this python tag will show you the error. Getting my point, guys? Yes or no? So, how many required fields are there?
Sunny: Right? For the application. Whether the data type is correct or not, the type of the variable are the correct or not. Valid range, okay, the data comes inside the valid range.
Sunny: and the correct format, okay? So everything, guys, we can validate using what? Using the pyntic itself. So guys, I'm going to be right one more line over here, just try to focus, okay?
Sunny: So, see, guys, what is this? Pyrentic data… Parentic is called to Data Validation and schema Library. On the other hand, if we're talking about the Pyrentic AI. So, Pyrentic AI is what… it is an Agentic framework for building the Agentic AI application.
Sunny: built around the Parentic style, type safety. So, it is a framework for building the AI agent, similar to the Langrau. So, if you don't know about the Pyrentic AI, you can go and check out the documentation. The documentation is quite good, you can easily understand the concept of the Parentic AI from there, okay?
Sunny: And even if you wanted to implement, you can implement it from there.
Sunny: Making sense, yes or no?
Sunny: Okay. Now, guys, here, guys, I'm going to be writing a couple of more definitions, so just try to focus, okay? So for, this definition is also going to be important, so I'm just writing it for all of you, so that, later on you can go through with this entire definition and all, and you can revise the concept.
Sunny: This pythontec AI, framework is not similar to the Langraph. Langraph is a little bit different, but yeah, it is for the same kind of work.
Sunny: So, it is also for creating an AI agent, this Parentic AI. Now, Pyntic is a Python library used to define the expected structure of the data and validate incoming data against the structure. If you're not getting this particular point, guys, you will get it in some time, once I'll show you the example.
Sunny: Now, Parentic helped us define what our data should look like, and checks whether the received data follows the structure, okay? So, in short, I can say we are going to be check the… we are just going to be perform the validation of the data, okay?
Sunny: pythonic is a Python library that let us define the expected structure of data using Python types, and automatically validate the input data against the structure, right? So this particular definition is having similar kind of meaning. Maybe this definition is not being clear right now, but once I show you the example, at that time, it will be clarified.
Sunny: Now, guys, schema enforcing. Now, there is one more term which you will find out while you are implementing this, while you are implementing this data validation and all. So, that is called the schema enforcing. So, here you can see the schema enforcing. So, schema enforcing, basically, schema enforcing simply means
Sunny: Making sure the data follow the structure and rules we have already defined.
Sunny: That is what, that is what, that is a schema enforcing, okay? Now, for example, if our schema says name should be string, and A should be integer, then the incoming data should follow these particular rules. And that is what, guys, that is a schema enforcing.
Sunny: Now, schema definition, defining what the data structure should look like, schema validation, checking whether the input data follows the defined structure, and then in schema, enforcing. So, let me write these points also over here.
Sunny: schema enforcing. Okay, so schema enforcing means what? Ensuring that invalid data is not accepted, and that defined structure and rule are followed, right? So guys, this is some sort of a theoretical point. Maybe some of you are getting this point, some of you are not getting this point.
Sunny: But don't worry, guys, once I will show you the example, after that, this, all the point, the entire point will be clarified. Got it, guys? Yes or no? If you're good to go till here, then please give me a quick thumbs up.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay. Now, guys, let's do one thing. Let's, start with a couple of examples, right? So here, guys, I'm, going to be…
Sunny: I'm going to be basically, draw one more, line diagram, okay? Just for your more understanding, so here is the one.
Sunny: So, let's say we have a raw data, right? Then, guys, we have a parentic schema. Then, using the Pyrentic schema, basically, we are doing the type checking.
Sunny: type conversion, constraint, okay, we are putting some constraint, we are doing some validation of the data, and what we will get, we will get the valid python object. Now, where we are using this pythonic inside our Agentic AI application.
Sunny: Right? So that also you will get once I will show you the end-to-end flow. Even though I have shown you in my previous classes, if you will go and check out over there, so we have already defined the Pyntic schema, okay, and we were using inside are those workflows. Now, one thing I would like to know to all… know from all of you, guys, have you seen those, base model?
Sunny: Have you seen those base models? In the previous class, have you seen those base models, yes or no?
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Yes or no, guys?
Sunny: So, if you have seen the base model, guys, so the base model only.
Sunny: Using the base model only, we are going to be convert any sort of a class into the pyntic class. So, let me write a couple of more points over here, so that you will get some more idea. So, what is a base model? So, here I written.
Sunny: Base model, basically. So, you will see this everywhere, this base model, okay? You will see this everywhere, this base model for the pythic imported class, for the pythonic class, right?
Sunny: So, any class, if I wanted to convert into the Bentic class, then for that, we are going to be import the space model, okay? Now, here you can see what we have. We have class.
Sunny: Class name is what user? We are inheriting this base model. Now, here you can see the name and the agent, age.
Sunny: This is what, guys, this is why. This is what, this is my class, okay, this is my variable inside the class, parameter. So, base model gives your class the pyntic capability, like validation, parsing, serialization, JSON schema, error message.
Sunny: Now, without base model, if you are not going to define this base model, guys, in that case, this is just going to be a normal pythonic class, okay? So, if you wanted to convert any sort of a class into the pythonteic class, then what you will do, guys, for that, tell me.
Sunny: Woody will do for that?
Sunny: Tell me.
Sunny: If we wanted to convert any sort of a class into the
Sunny: parented class, then, for that, you are going to be…
Sunny: You're going to be, like,
Sunny: inherit the base model class, okay? Great.
Sunny: Now, guys, let's understand couple of more things, okay? Let's understand couple of more things. Now, see, if you wanted to use the python take, so for that, there is some command, let me write inside the markdown only, so then later on, you can take this command from here.
Sunny: So you need to be in… run this command, ubpip install, right?
Sunny: So just run this command ubpip install pydentic, and you will be able to install the python tick inside your base model. So the same thing I can mention inside the requirement.txt also. So whenever you are going to be, download something from the requirement.txt, then, this python tag will also be included over there. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So, here is what… here is my parent take. Now, guys, Pirant is having their recent version. The version is called the version 2, okay? So, you will find out some major changes when you're going to be use the version 2, Pyntic version 2.
Sunny: So, when I was using Python… when I was using the python take, at that time, I have faced this, like, issue a lot, okay, with the pyntic version 2.
Sunny: So let me highlight a couple of points over here with respect to this Pyrentic version 2. Later on, we are going to be implemented in the form of code as well. So what I can do, guys, I can keep it over here and see. Pyrentic version 1, major API changes in the Pyntic version 2.
Sunny: Okay. Now guys, what all changes are there? So let me highlight those changes. It's just the function name, which they have modified a little bit.
Sunny: So, here I can mention those names.
Sunny: I hope, guys, you are able to see this particular name. Just let me know if you are able to see this name.
Sunny: Tell me yes.
Sunny: If you're able to see this name, just let me know in the chat, okay? So, dict become model dump, JSON become model dump, model dump JSON,
Sunny: parse object method, become model validator, model validate JSON, okay? If you're not getting it right now, once I'll show you the example and all, at that time, this entire idea is going to be clear. So, guys, I hope you understood this entire theoretical point. Let me revise this entire theoretical point.
Sunny: Okay, so why we are using this pythonic? So, pythonic, basically, we are going to be used to validate the data. Got it? If the data is going to be validated correctly, then we will not get any error. If the data is not getting validated correctly, then we will face error, okay? Now here, pythonic and Pyntic AI both are the different thing.
Sunny: Got it. Then, guys, there are… there is a couple of definitions, which you can read it out.
Sunny: Okay, again, I'm not going to read this definition. Now, I have clarified a couple of terms over here. First is a schema defining, second is a schema validation, and third is a schema enforcing. Schema defining, basically, are going to be defined as a schema class, basically.
Sunny: Schema validation means you are going to be checking that schema, whether it is working fine or not. Schema enforcing means it's just a term, right? So you are just checking whatever schema you are going to be defined.
Sunny: It is valid or not, okay? It is… it means we can pass the valid data to that or not, right? Schema… I've defined a schema as following the rule or not, okay? So that, specific thing is called the schema enforcing. Got it? So schema enforcing is just a simple term.
Sunny: Now, again, guys, you can see one more line diagram with respect to the pythontec. Now, here, guys, I have given the explanation with respect to the base model. If you're not going to inherit the base model, then your class is going to be a simple pythonic class. Got it, guys?
Sunny: how to install the pyntic. So, here is a command for installing the pythonic. Now, there is some changes inside the latest version of the pydentic when you are going to be utilizing it. Maybe at that time, you will get to know, right? So these are some changes, basically, which I have highlighted over here.
Sunny: Right? I hope this theoretical point is clear. So guys, can we go ahead with some practical?
Sunny: If you'll, say yes, sir, then, basically I can go ahead.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Now, what I'm going to do, guys, so here, first I'll give you the comparison without Pydentic and with Pydentic, what is a differences? You will find out inside the code, right? So, first, what we will do, we'll understand the differences without Pydentic versus with Pydentic.
Sunny: So, let me write the heading over here, without pairedic, or with pydentic. So, my goal, basically… what is my goal, guys? So, I wanted to verify the name, age… okay. So, I wanted to verify this two-parameter of any sort of a person.
Sunny: Right? So, what I will do, guys, I will take an input.
Sunny: Let me write over here. I'll take an input, wrong.
Sunny: user, Now, inside the input, In the input, I will ask, I will ask there.
Sunny: Name.
Sunny: And… H.
Sunny: Okay? Now, over the age also, I'm going to put some criteria.
Sunny: So the age, basically, should be greater than 18.
Sunny: Understood, guys? Did you understand the problem statement? Now, if you are going to be solved this particular problem statement, how you are going to do that?
Sunny: How you're going to be doing that in the Python code?
Sunny: So, let's say if I'm, so here, guys, what I'm doing, I'm going to be create.
Sunny: I'm going to be create one function. So this is, like, without parenting.
Sunny: So, my function name is what? Let's say, create underscore.
Sunny: user. Now, what it will do, guys, it will take the data.
Sunny: Okay? Now here, guys, what I will do, first I'll check the name of the person.
Sunny: So, if name, okay, name, not in, not in inside the data.
Sunny: Okay, let me write over here data. Then, guys, what I will do, tell me… so here, guys, I'm going to be ra… here, guys, I'm going to be raised the exception. Got it? Then what I'm doing, guys, I'm checking. So, what should be the data type of the name? Can anyone tell me what should be the data type of the name?
Sunny: So, here the data type of the name should be the…
Sunny: is string, right? So here, I'm going to write that particular logic. So this is the logic, guys, just see.
Sunny: Okay, if not instance, date name is SDR, then again we are going to erase the error.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, what I'm doing, so here, okay, you can keep it value error, exception, anything. Exception, actually, it's a parent class. Now, let's check about the age. If age is not there, then what I'll do, guys, if age is not there.
Sunny: Then again, I'm going to be raise the error. As simple as that, okay? Then, guys, here I'm going to be check the data type of the age. If it is not integer, then again, I'm going to be raise the error.
Sunny: And then, guys, what I will do, so here is one more thing. A should be greater than 18. Let me put one more condition over here. So here, guys, the condition, basically, if the age is less than 18, in that case, again, we are going to be… raise what? We are going to be raised the exception.
Sunny: Making sense to all of you, yes or no?
Sunny: If everything is fine.
Sunny: Then, guys, what I will do, I will return the data. So here, guys, what I'm doing, guys, I'm going to be return the data.
Sunny: Now, if anyone… if everyone is able to understand this entire function, then please let me know in the chat.
Sunny: You can say, sir, yes, we are good to go with this entire function.
Sunny: You can proceed.
Sunny: Right? So first, guys, what I'm doing. So here I am, I have a user data.
Sunny: So, in the user data, basically, I can take a data from anyone. So, guys, can you tell me your age?
Sunny: I can write it down in the chat. Sorry, you can write it on the chat, I will mention inside the name, okay?
Sunny: So, inside the cell itself. So, Kumar Gaurav is saying, I am 35-year-old, great Kumar, so let me, write your
Sunny: Name.
Sunny: Kumar Gaurav.
Sunny: So, the age is… 35. Now, guys, if I'm, running… if I'm passing this particular data.
Sunny: If I'm passing this particular data to the create user, now tell me, guys, Now, tell me, guys,
Sunny: Gaurav, sorry. So, it's a Gaurav, Kumar Gaurav. So, guys, tell me, will it be passed, or it will fail?
Sunny: It's going to be pass, or it's going to be fail.
Sunny: It's going to be… Pass, guys. So here, guys, you will see we are able to get a result.
Sunny: So, this result, this data I'm passing to this create user, Okay, now see the result.
Sunny: user created successfully, because this Kumar Gaurav and the ages, both criteria is matching. Let's pass the detail of some other user. So, what I can do, guys, I can pass the name and detail of the Mayank.
Sunny: So, Mayank is 49 year old, okay.
Sunny: That's great, Mayank.
Sunny: Now, here I can write the age. Now, tell me, guys, whether it's going to be pass or not.
Sunny: So, again, guys, this data is also going to be pass.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: this data is also going to be passed. Now, let me pass something over here, something different. So, let's say there is one user
Sunny: Who is?
Sunny: Mayank, let's say the name is Mayank Singh.
Sunny: Now, the age is what? The age is 70. Now, tell me, guys, this time is going to be passed, or what?
Sunny: It's going to be passed, or it's going to be fail. So let's see, let's, run it again.
Sunny: So, here is a person, Mayank Singh, the age is around 17. So, see, it is saying age must be greater than or equal to 18. So, this time, it's not going to be passed. The same thing we can check out with the, basically, name also. So, here, let's say if I'm going to be write a name.
Sunny: My name is Sunny. Now, tell me, guys, whether it's going to be pass or fail.
Sunny: if I'm going to be writing without a string, then it's going to be fail. Okay, all let's write as a list, let's see.
Sunny: whether the list will be passed or not. So, I'm passing in the form of list.
Sunny: So, this is the list, and the age is… my age is 30, okay?
Sunny: So, my age is 30.
Sunny: Now I can run it, and create user.
Sunny: And this time, guys, what I will do, I will pass the data. Now, see.
Sunny: So, we are getting error. So, are you able to understand about this validation code? How many of you are able to understand about this validation code? So, one thing I would like to ask to everyone. So, now here, did I use any pythonic modeling to validate… to validate this entire thing?
Sunny: No, we are not going to be use any python modeling.
Sunny: Okay? Without padding modeling only, just by writing this particular logic, we are able to do that.
Sunny: The same thing we can do using the pythic also. Now, let me show you how much opti… how much, like, level of… how much level of optimization we can perform. You…
Sunny: using the pydentic. So, what I'm doing here, guys, I'm going to create the pythontec model now. So, let me create the pythontec model. Let me validate this entire thing using the pythonic model itself. So, what I can do for that… so first, guys, I'll import the base model.
Sunny: So, from…
Sunny: pythonic Base Model. Now, I'm going to import this field also. Valuation error, I will import later on.
Sunny: I'll show you this validation error also. So, here is what? Field.
Sunny: The spelling is not correct, that's why it is giving me error.
Sunny: So, we have base model, and we have field. Now, what I'll do, guys, I will create one class, okay? So my class name is going to be what? My class name is going to be user. Now, what I'll do, guys, I will basically take a name. Name should be STR, and A should be integer.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, you can see. So, is it clear? What is this field? Can anyone tell me what is this field?
Sunny: Do you understand, this… the meaning of the field, guys?
Sunny: So I capped the explanation about the field as well, so let me,
Sunny: Show you that, explanation of the field.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, just, just, look over here. I am putting, this detail right after this one. So, just, read it out. So, what I've written, what is a field?
Sunny: Okay, example is this one. So let's say we have an age, the type of the age should be integer. So in the field, basically, what we are going to be mentioned… in the field, basically, we are going to be mentioned the description, as well as the parameter, okay? Greater than, or the lower than, right?
Sunny: equal, whatever, basically, you can mention, you can write inside the field. So, fields let you add validation rules, description, some default value, some construction constraint, and the metadata.
Sunny: So this field method, this field method, basically, just to add some additional detail.
Sunny: Getting my point? Yes or no? So, field is for what? Field, basically, just to add some additional detail, like rule, description, some default value, constraint, metadata. So, here you can see, field greater than zero.
Sunny: Okay? It's a greater than.
Sunny: Then less than, okay?
Sunny: Less than equal to.
Sunny: Right? Less than or equal to. Minimum length, max length. So this kind of parameter you can pass where you can pass inside the field.
Sunny: So, this is clear, guys, what is a field? So, field is a method where, basically, we can pass some additional information, some additional parameter, just to validate the
Sunny: just to validate that specific variable, okay? You can read it, you can read it, and it will be clarified. The concept of the field is going to be clarified.
Sunny: Now, if you will look into this particular example, so you'll find out what… see. So, we have a field, so name, the type of the name should be string, so this is just a description. Now, age, basically, so here you can see.
Sunny: the value should be greater than or equal to 18, okay? Now, let me do the same thing using this pythontec modeling also. So, can I, check out this pydentic modeling, guys? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: So let's check out the pythontec modeling.
Sunny: what I will do, guys, nothing I'll do over here.
Sunny: It's very simple.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So here, I will pass the value.
Sunny: I'll pass the value of what? I will pass the value of this name and the age, just to validate this entire thing. So, just give me a second, guys, I'm putting the value of it.
Sunny: Oh, okay.
Sunny: Yeah, so how I can install this class?
Sunny: Let me write over here, user.
Sunny: Right, and then I can pass the name.
Sunny: name, let's say Mayank CHUGH, and the age is 49. So, this is what, guys, this is my pythonic object.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: If I'm going to be running, guys, see, my pythontec object is initialized. Now, what I'll do, guys, I'll write the user.name.
Sunny: Okay, user.name.
Sunny: So, guys, if I'll run it, guys, see, I'm getting a name. If I'll write user.h, user.h, what I'll get, guys, I will get the H.
Sunny: Understood, is it clear or not? So, let's say if I'm going to be passed some other value, so instead of this, like, name and age, I'm passing some other name and age. So, let's say if I'm writing over here, Sunny, and the age is going to be, let's say.
Sunny: 16.
Sunny: Right? Or 17. Now, in that case, guys, it's not going to be pass. Why it's not going to be passed? Tell me. Because, guys, here, you can see…
Sunny: The age is not greater than… the age is not greater than 18.
Sunny: Now, see, earlier, we were able… we were able to do the same thing, but just see over here, how much, basically, code we have written for this entire thing, right? How much manual code we have written for this entire thing.
Sunny: Now, this thing basically is being someone… by someone, right? So we are just going to be using that functionality in the form of objects, okay? This entire functionality is an abstract. Some… someone has written it in a backend. We are going to be installed that particular package as a pydentic package.
Sunny: Right? And, now just see the level of optimization. What I've done, guys, so I've just defined the data, this pyntic class, okay? Our user is schema.
Sunny: And then, guys, we are able to pass the information.
Sunny: Right? If it is correct, guys, according to this schema.
Sunny: according to this schema, if it is correct, guys, then it will not generate any sort of an error. If according to the schema it is not correct, then it will showcase the error. We can check out with any sort of a value, you will get it.
Sunny: Now, let's do one thing. Let's, write something over here. So, let's say here is my user. Now, here the name, basically, the name could be anything. The name is the Ankit, okay?
Sunny: Ankit Singh.
Sunny: Now, guys, here what I'm doing, instead of the age, I'm writing some value. Let's say age is what?
Sunny: 49, okay?
Sunny: 49.
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, whether it will run it, or whether it will run, or it will generate the error, if I'm going to be passing like this. If I'm going to be run it, guys, so here, it's going to be create.
Sunny: Okay? No, it will run. Why it will run, guys? Because internally, it will handle this. This 49 string, it will be handled as a integer, okay? Internally, it will convert that. But instead of this one, if I'm writing like this, let's say instead of the 49, if I'm writing 40,
Sunny: 9. Now, tell me, this time, whether it's going to be pass or fail this time.
Sunny: Now, guys, this time, actually, it's going to be fail.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: At this time, it will not work. But if I'm going to be righted like this, then it will work. So tell me, is it getting killer? A simple, simple example, I think everyone is able to understand this entire thing.
Sunny: Just to validate. Now, where you can use this entire piling tick and all. I'll discuss that, okay? So I'll show you one full-fledged Langra workflow.
Sunny: or they are basically, definitely, we are going to be discussed. Now, let me, basically, give you a couple of more examples. So, here, what I'm doing, guys, so let's say this is my flow. Just, look over the flow.
Sunny: So my flow is basically my user wanted to do some registration, okay? User registration. It's having a sign-up form, then it is… the detail is going to the backend API.
Sunny: the backend API basically is validating that user. Now, for that, guys, what we require, tell me if I wanted to perform this particular flow, so I required one, python tick class. So here, guys, I'm going to create one class.
Sunny: user registration class. Now, in the user registration class, just see over here what we have.
Sunny: So, in the user registration class, basically, we have
Sunny: name, email, and age, okay? Now, this email SDR, you can directly import it from the… you can directly import it from where? From the…
Sunny: pydentic itself. So let me show you the import statement again. So this is my pyntic import statement, okay, so I'm writing the email SDR and this validation error also, right?
Sunny: So, email HDR is there. So, this email SDR, we can directly, like, import from the parentic itself, or else, you can use the field to decide… to define some custom description also. That is also fine.
Sunny: Now, here, field is saying greater than, equal to 18. So, this is my use and registration, this is my use and registration, basically, class.
Sunny: Just to validate the, user, schema.
Sunny: Okay, so first of all, guys, let me run that import statement, otherwise it will again give me the error. It was giving me the import error.
Sunny: Now, again, I'm going to be executed. Now, see, the class has initialized. I'm going to perform the user registration. So, this is my, name, this is my email, and here is my age. I'll be passing that. Okay, now see, the user has registered.
Sunny: I can check out the detail of the user, so you can simply, call the variable over here. Username, okay?
Sunny: Email and the age. You can get those details. Every sort of a value, you can get it, okay, like this. You can put the dot over here, okay? So here is… you can see the email, and if you wanted to check out the age, you can simply put this age parameter.
Sunny: Now, see, guys, we are getting the age also. I hope this is fine. So, what I'm doing, guys, now, this time.
Sunny: I'm going to be writing something. So, see, this is, again, one of my users. So, the age could be 19 of this user. Now, here, instead of the email I'm writing.
Sunny: Sunny.
Sunny: Savita, right?
Sunny: So now tell me, guys, this time, whether it's going to be work, or it's going to be generate the error.
Sunny: what I'll get over here, tell me.
Sunny: So, guys, here, basically, I will get the
Sunny: Error, right? So let me show you, see.
Sunny: It's showing the error. So it's showing… email should not be like this. Email should follow the add symbol, right? At the red symbol.
Sunny: If you're going to be passed an email like this, then it's not going to be walled. Understood, guys? So, the same thing, basically, it could be done… sorry, I can check out again this particular thing, I can pass the 16 over here. Let's see, so this time it is saying… it is telling 2 validation error.
Sunny: Okay? So tell me, guys, if it is going to be showing you this validation error, in that case, your program will shut down, or your program will be running.
Sunny: Tell me.
Sunny: If you're getting this particular error, the validation error, so in that case, what will happen? Your program will shut down, or your program will be running as it is.
Sunny: So, here, guys, your program is going to be shutted down.
Sunny: Right? So what we do for that, we use the exception heading, right? So let me show you the same example in the exception handling. So what I can do, I can use the try and the accept blocks. So here I'm writing the try, okay?
Sunny: So, this is my user. Now, guys, what I'll do, I'll write the accept block also. So, accept validation error. And then, guys, what I'm doing, I'm going to be printing the E, the detail of the error.
Sunny: Now, guys, here you will see, if I'm running the same example, this wrong example, what you will get, guys? You will be getting this particular message, right? So, there is two ways.
Sunny: First, if you're going to be write it directly, then it will…
Sunny: terminate the application, okay? It will terminate the flow.
Sunny: If you wanted to handle this particular exception, what you can do, you can simply use a try and accept blog. So this validation error, basically, you can import from the pythonic itself. So in the try, you can write your main code. If it is having some sort of issue, then it will come into the accept blog, and then accept blog, basically, will give you the error detail.
Sunny: Making sense, yes or no. So, in the industry, we…
Sunny: we do this thing. So, whenever we develop any sort of a program, SOAP,
Sunny: There is two things. First, basically, to raise the error, right? To complete… to completely shut down the program, right? The program cannot be go-ahead after getting that particular error. The second, basically, to handle that error, to log that error, okay? To log that error.
Sunny: Okay, so whether you're going to be raise it, or you're going to be log that error, you need to decide that. Understood, yes or no? So this thing, we are going to be understanding in our end-to-end project also, when to raise the issue, and when to handle or when to log that issue.
Sunny: Understood. If this part is getting clearer, guys, please let me know in the chat.
Sunny: Yes? So, are you liking the session?
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, I have written some sort of an explanation also, so I can give you those particular explanation.
Sunny: And, now I can keep this explanation over here.
Sunny: So just read it out, this explanation, it is an important one, you will get some idea. So just to… so… so that… see, why I'm, why I'm writing this, all the theoretical points, and also that, later on, you can, revise the concepts, okay? So for that only, basically, I'm mentioning all the points and all. Got it?
Sunny: Good. So, this is fine. Now, let's do one thing, guys. Let's, basically, take some more examples.
Sunny: So, guys, do you want the break, or
Sunny: Should I continue with a morde example?
Sunny: Okay? Let's look into some more examples, then, by 9.15, I will give you the break. So over here, guys, see.
Sunny: not only this one, we can, basically validate a couple of more things. So, I'm, showing you some more examples. So, tell me, guys, what is this?
Sunny: What is this one? This class?
Sunny: This class is related to what? This class product.
Sunny: Tell me, guys, if we're talking about the class product, it is related to what? This class product, actually, it is related to the e-commerce validation, product validation, that we write over here. The AWAB example was related to what? The AWAB example, basically, it was related to the
Sunny: It was related to the API validation. Okay, this particular example which I've given you.
Sunny: This is belonging to the API validation. So let me, write over here, this is basically…
Sunny: related to the API validation, okay? So the command itself, I'm going to be mentioned, so then, whenever you will look into the… this notebook, you'll feel that this example is near to the real time, okay? API validation. We can mention so many things while we are validating the data.
Sunny: So, yeah. Now, here you can see, the product validation. So, let me create a class. Name should be there, price, quantity should be there. It's all about the product, basically, which we are talking about. So.
Sunny: let's say this is my schema. I'm going to be defining the… this is my schema definition, and this is my schema creation, right? And this… all the… this entire thing is called the enforcing schema. Got it?
Sunny: So, product is there, the name is the laptop, price is $75,000, and the quantity is 5. Now, tell me whether it's going to be run it, or it's going to be generate the error.
Sunny: Fast, guys.
Sunny: I would like to know in the chat whether it's going to be generated the error, or it's going to be run it, like, successfully.
Sunny: Yeah, if you have any sort of example, Krish, or anyone, guys, you can ask me in the doubt session, I'll be discussing over there. Got it?
Sunny: So, here, if I'm running it, guys, it will run it successfully, because all the criteria is meeting, no?
Sunny: all the criteria is meeting to the schema. So, this is my schema.
Sunny: Does what guys tell me this is my schema.
Sunny: Okay, and here we are going to be initialize this schema. We are going to be validating this schema. Now, I'm giving you one more example. Now, tell me, guys, whether it's going to be run it, or it's going to be, basically generate the error.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: So if I'm running it, guys, it will… generate the error.
Sunny: Okay, I hope this is also clear.
Sunny: We cannot provide the… we cannot provide the negative value.
Sunny: So you can put this kind of validation.
Sunny: Now, guys, let me show you one more kind of example. So, you know about the banking transactions.
Sunny: So when we are going to be develop that kind of application, so at that time also, we can do some schema enforcing.
Sunny: Now, what kind of schema enforcing is required over here?
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys… Can we create this kind of schema? Sender account, receiver account, and the amount?
Sunny: Is it getting clear? All the fields are getting clear. Sender account, receiver account, and the amount. Let's say if I wanted to validate it.
Sunny: So let's say… let's suppose, guys, this is a sender account. This is a receiver account, and the amount is, let's say.
Sunny: 50 lakh rupees, right? So if I'm transferring this much of amount, then tell me whether it will generate the error, or it will run it fine.
Sunny: If I'm going to be executed, guys, not tell me. It will run it? Fine.
Sunny: Because all the value are meeting to this particular criteria, okay, this is schema. So, see, this is the values. Now, over here, guys, if I'm putting something wrong, let's say my amount is going to be negative, right? Something like this. Now, tell me this time, it will generate the error.
Sunny: the value should not be a negative 1. Or else I can put some conditions over here, greater than, let's say 5,500 rupees.
Sunny: Right? Now, tell me, guys, are you getting the messages when the balance is going to be low, let's say below $500 or below $5,000, something like that? It depends account to account, right? Anyone?
Sunny: Who is having 500 rupees inside the account.
Sunny: Everyone is having correct.
Sunny: So… Someone is like, no, sir, I have 5 rupees.
Sunny: Sir, I have… you have, 5 lakh.
Sunny: May I pass you 5 rupees over.
Sunny: I agree.
Sunny: You have dollars, right? Yeah, even I have a loan.
Sunny: great.
Sunny: So, now let's check it out. It is giving me the error. You can put the, basically this one, some constraint also, and if you are going to be initialize the schema, so let's say, in my account, let's say I have 400 rupees.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Amount… amount is what?
Sunny: Amount is 400 I'm sending from my account to mine.
Sunny: Poor friend's account. So, this is the amount 400. Now, see, it is giving me the error.
Sunny: This is a sender account, this is a receiver account, and I'm just sending 400 rupees. So it is saying, okay, so you cannot send the 400 rupees, at least the amount should be 500. Many times we are getting this error when we are sending money from here to there, there to here, right? That's it.
Sunny: So, fine guys, now if I'm putting the value like this, so let's say if I'm putting the value like this…
Sunny: Just tell me, guys, whether it will work or not.
Sunny: So, instead of the 4T, I'm putting 4TL.
Sunny: So, whether it will work, or it will generate the error.
Sunny: It's not closed.
Sunny: It's closed now.
Sunny: Huh. Now here, what I'm doing, I'm putting L.
Sunny: Now, it will generate the error. It is saying invalid value, so I can put it into the string.
Sunny: Now tell me, guys, so see. Again, the validation error.
Sunny: Something like this, right? So, yeah, I hope you are able to understand the use of this Pyntic class.
Sunny: Yes or no?
Sunny: Now, one more thing I see. Whenever you're going to define the LLM, you're going to be the LLM.
Sunny: Okay. At that time, Can you validate this LLM-related details using this pythontec schema?
Sunny: Yes, we can do that. So, here, I have created one.
Sunny: Pyntic class, just to get the…
Sunny: configuration of our LLM, okay?
Sunny: LLM configuration. So, here, basically.
Sunny: model configuration class. Just see over here how we… how we can define this one.
Sunny: model configuration class. So, I have created one more class. I'm just going to be copy and paste.
Sunny: So, the class name is the model configuration. So, where we are getting the model name, that should be string, temperature, and the timeout error.
Sunny: timeout, basically, this particular value. So, yeah, these kind of classes we can configure, and going forward, I will show you how to utilize these classes.
Sunny: So, maybe in the, basically, end-to-end project, we are going to integrate this entire thing. Got it? Now, let's say my model is the GPD model, temperature is something, and the timeout is 30.
Sunny: So this is the configuration, guys. This will pass, because all the value is… all the value is meeting to this particular criteria.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, let's suppose if I'm passing the temperature 3. So, temperature could be 3 of any model.
Sunny: Temperature could be 3 of any model, or 2.1, no, right? It's not going to be warped. So if I'm going to be running, guys, it is giving me the error.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, here you can see greater than zero, let's say timeout value if I'm going to be passed something like this.
Sunny: So I can take this particular example, and I can basically pass the timeout value, let's say minus 5. So in that case, also, it's going to be generate the error.
Sunny: So these, value, the modulated value also, you can validate using the pythontec object. So going forward, we are going to discuss all this thing in our end-to-end project. We will discuss it.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no? So, all the examples are clear.
Sunny: I will show you many more examples. Now, one more thing we have discussed. If you remember, guys,
Sunny: In our previous example, I discussed one thing.
Sunny: That is a structure output.
Sunny: Right? So…
Sunny: Structure output is the important one, and let me show you how to generate the structure output using this pythonting model.
Sunny: So, for that, I required the LLM. Here, I'm writing from Langchain.
Sunny: underscore… Grog.
Sunny: And then import.
Sunny: Chet Grok. Okay?
Sunny: So, let me import this.
Sunny: GR?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, this is what, guys, this is my class. Now, I will…
Sunny: basically create an object of this class. So, see, this is the object. Okay? Here's the object, guys. Now, what I'll do, guys, so here, let me check it out, whether it's working fine or not. So, I'll simply use the invoke method.
Sunny: dot invoke.
Sunny: Now, here I will write, what is the capital of the France. It's giving me the… it's giving me the answer, means the model is working fine.
Sunny: Now, what I'm doing, guys, so here, I'm creating one class. The class name is what? The class name is the personal detail.
Sunny: So we have a name of the person, age of the person, and the city of the person.
Sunny: Okay? City of the person. This feature is very, very important for the Agentic application, guys. That's why I'm discussing it again, even though I have shown in my previous code itself. So let's say the class name is what? Person Details. Okay? Now here, guys, what I'll do, I'll take this, LLM,
Sunny: And now I'll call one method on top of it. Can anyone tell me what could be the method?
Sunny: The method name is basically width, structure, is structural.
Sunny: output. Now, here I will pass the personal detail.
Sunny: Okay, now I'll assign this thing inside the variable that is a structure model. Got it, guys? Now, this is what, guys. I have a model. Now my model is ready with the structure output capability, okay, with a pythonte capability. I can invoke it with a prompt, so here I'm writing invoke.
Sunny: And now, guys, I can…
Sunny: write something, okay? So, I can write over here, I can write one message, so my message is…
Sunny: Sunny is 30-year-old and lives in Delhi, right? So, this is my message. Now, tell me what output I'll get from here. If I'm going to execute this particular thing, right? So, here you will see the output.
Sunny: C.
Sunny: Name is Sunny, age is 30, and output is… city is the deli. So I've given this particular, prompt.
Sunny: and I define this as schema, okay? And I define this as schema, then I pass this schema to the LLM.
Sunny: I initialize the model, and whatever message I'm giving to the model, so model is able to extract those specific entity from the data itself. If you remember, in our previous… if you remember, guys, so in the previous code.
Sunny: I have created this kind of class. Tell me.
Sunny: Are able to remember this one.
Sunny: are able to remember this one. So, we have created this particular class. So, we were having two… we were having the route and the reasoning.
Sunny: Route means which route it is going to be take, whether it's a RAG, web, or LLM. Reasoning means what kind of reasoning it is doing when it is taking a route, okay? So this kind of class we had created, and with that, basically, we were deciding our route.
Sunny: So, guys, this particular feature is very, very important inside the Agentic AI, and going forward, we are going to be used a lot this particular feature. Got it, guys? Yes or no? Tell me if this part is getting killer.
Sunny: Now, here I have created some classes, right?
Sunny: But I have not shown you the end uses of these classes, so once I'll create a project, guys, the next project, the end-to-end flow, basically, so at that time, I'll be creating this model using the pydentic, the schema, basically, using the pythonic, and then everything, everything means everything I'm going to be validated using this pyntic model.
Sunny: So just wait for one or two more classes, right? You will see some use cases around to this thing.
Sunny: Now, I hope this entire thing is clear, so just give me quick thumbs up if you're able to get it, until I can give you this entire code.
Sunny: So, here is the code, guys, and this is the Rakan.txt.
Sunny: And this is my rough work, so code updated.
Sunny: Okay, code is updated, I haven't done these changes, now let me get push.
Sunny: So, did you get the code or not? Just, let me know in the chat.
Sunny: If you got it. Then, after the break, guys, I will show you the more and more example. I have so many different examples. We'll discuss those examples. So, can we go for the break now? We'll take 20-minute break, the quick dinner break.
Sunny: And then, guys, we'll complete a couple of more things inside the pythonic itself, okay? So many, different things I'm going to show you then. I'm going to show you, guys, don't worry. You will, get it, okay? For sure.
Sunny: Link is already there, no? Just search it over the Google, Sunny Savita GitHub, you will get…
Sunny: And check out the first report.
Sunny: If you don't have the link of the GitHub, then again, I can ping you. Wait.
Sunny: So guys, let's take a break, then, let's meet after the break. Thank you very much.
Sunny: Okay, guys, I think we can start with the session.
Sunny: If everyone is there, please let me know in the chat.
Sunny: Yeah, okay, great. So, what I'm doing, so I'm going to show you a couple of more examples of the pythonic.
Sunny: So, whatever I have shown you so far, I hope those points are clear.
Sunny: just let me know so that I will get some idea. I have shared the code as well, you can directly take the code from the GitHub itself.
Sunny: Got it.
Sunny: Yup.
Sunny: So, now, what I'm doing, guys, so, here I am writing a couple of more examples, couple of more functionality, whatever functionality which, basically are going to be used, very, very frequently in the practical term, okay?
Sunny: So, the first one is what? Whatever method I have shown you, right, earlier. So, all the method, basically, I'll be, calling over here, on top of this, is schema.
Sunny: Okay, now, here I'm writing one class, guys. See?
Sunny: If you're able to see this class.
Sunny: And please, let me know in the chat.
Sunny: Is it visible?
Sunny: This one?
Sunny: whatever thing I have faced when I was doing the practical.
Sunny: sorry, when I was developing the project, whatever thing, whatever kind of, functionality I have implemented with respect to the project, in a real-time project, I'm saying. So, though everything, like, I have included inside this notebook, at the end, you will get every sort of a concept.
Sunny: Now, what is the meaning of this different, different parameter? So, whenever we are going to be defining the class, okay, so what I can do, guys, I can take a copy of it.
Sunny: And let's write in a clean manner. So let me comment this out right now.
Sunny: So, here, I'm going to remove this one.
Sunny: Then… this one.
Sunny: than this one.
Sunny: And then this one.
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, how many values we have. So, if you will see, so we have 4 values.
Sunny: Now, the first one, basically, name. Name STR, okay? It's a mandatory one. Now, country is a STR, okay? Now, here you will find out some by-default value. So, India is what? It's a by default value. If you're not passing anything.
Sunny: Yeah. So we are not passing anything while we are creating this, object, okay? While we are creating an object of the user class, then the automatically this India value will be there. Middle name, STR.
Sunny: Okay, the type of the middle name is STR or none. Got it? Either it could be STR or it could be none. This pipe symbol, basically, it is representing to OR.
Sunny: Nickmame, STR, or none. Okay, now here, also, you can see the by default value of the nickname. So let's try to… now let's try to, like, validate… no, let's try to basically validate the values. So, here, guys, just see over here, tell me.
Sunny: whether it's going to work or not. This one. Let me write over here, USA.
Sunny: Tell me, guys, is it going to work, or it's going to fail?
Sunny: None means nothing. So, it's going to work, or it's going to be failed.
Sunny: We are passing Sunny, country is a USA, middle name is a Kumar, and then the nickname is a Sun.
Sunny: It's going to run or fail.
Sunny: It's going to be work, guys. See, if I'm executing it, so it's working. It's able to initialize.
Sunny: Name is Sunny, countries are USA, middle, name is KUMAR, and nickname is a Sun. How it is working?
Sunny: So, here you can see the name. Name sealed… name is coming over here. Country, basically, by default, is India.
Sunny: If we are not passing anything from here, then the by default value will be the India. Middle name, basically, it's a sr none, okay? So, either it could be sr none. So, here we are passing the string value. Nickmame, basically, what? s
Sunny: Or none, okay? And the by default value is what? By default value is none. Got it?
Sunny: So, let me execute, yeah, without field value also, we can initialize it like this. That will also work. Now, tell me, guys, whether this is going to work or not.
Sunny: That'll be fast.
Sunny: Is it going to work? Just look at the class and tell me what I'll get over here.
Sunny: what I will get over here.
Sunny: So if I will execute it, so here you will see…
Sunny: user, and see the user? Sunny is there.
Sunny: By default, the country is India.
Sunny: Middle name is KUMAR, and nickname is what? None.
Sunny: What is the by default value of the name, nickname? None. What is the by default value of the country? India. None means nothing.
Sunny: Okay? Is it clear?
Sunny: Yes or no? Tell me fast.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now tell me, guys, whether this is going to work or not, this one.
Sunny: Name is Sunny, middle name is Nun.
Sunny: Will it work?
Sunny: None means nothing. None means what? Nothing. Okay?
Sunny: None is not a special name. None means nothing.
Sunny: The meaning of none in python… the meaning of none is python is nothing, okay?
Sunny: So, here, you can see, if I'm going to be executed, so what I'll be getting, let me show you that.
Sunny: So here, the name is Sunny, this is right. Country is India, these are by default value. Middle name is nothing, nickname is nothing. None means nothing, right? So whenever we don't want to be initialized anyway, it means we can keep the none actually inside the variable, so that means nothing, okay? You can keep the blank or none. Got it?
Sunny: Yeah, both are a different one, you are right.
Sunny: So I hope, guys, this part is clear, and you are able to understand the meaning of it. Here, I've written a description. You can refer this particular cell just to understand the description of each and every parameter.
Sunny: Now, let me show you some other thing. So, here, guys, I'm going to be create.
Sunny: One more model.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, what we have over here. So, we have name, age, and city. Is it visible to all of you? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Yes? Okay. Now, guys, what I'm going to do over here, what I'm going to do over here, see, I'm going to call some specific functions.
Sunny: So, name, age would be there, and city would be the by default one. So, let me initialize this, particular user. So, here is a user. The username is Sunny, age is, what, 30. So, will it work, guys? Yes, definitely it will work.
Sunny: So, if I will show you the user, guys, see, I'm getting the user. Now, guys, tell me, if I wanted to get a value, if I wanted to get a value out of this user, how I can get it?
Sunny: If I wanted to get a value out of this user, see, this is a user object now, right? If I wanted to get a value of this from this user, I can simply put the name.
Sunny: I can get the name, I can put the age, Okay.
Sunny: If I'm putting the age, what I'm getting, guys, I'm getting the age. So, let's see if I'm putting the, basically, city over here. So, city. City is what? Bangalore, okay?
Sunny: Now, guys, let's suppose if I want to convert this user object, user pyntic object, right? If you will see the type of this user, so let me check the type of the user over here. See, the type of the user, basically, it's a class, right? It's a pydentic class.
Sunny: Now, guys, if I wanted to convert this particular user into the dictionary, so how I can do that? So, simply, I'll call one method on top of it.
Sunny: The method name is going to be what?
Sunny: So here, the method name is… dot model.
Sunny: Underscore, Tom.
Sunny: Is it clear, guys?
Sunny: So in the latest version of the python deck, you will have to call this method model dump instead of the as dict, okay? So that you can convert this one, this dictionary, into VR. Sorry, you can convert, basically, this, user detail into the dictionary.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Is it clear, guys? So, we have converted this user object, user detail, into the dictionary, right? Now, if I wanted to convert into the JSON, how I can convert into the JSON? Now, if you will check the type of it, so see, let's check the type of it, see, the type of the dict.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, if I wanted to convert this into the JSON, okay, so what I'll do, guys, I'll use the user, then I'll call the model, underscore term.
Sunny: JSON, okay? Now, once you will call it, guys, now see, what you're getting, you're getting a same object, same dictionary, but it is a string.
Sunny: Right? If I will check the type of it, so let me check the type of it.
Sunny: So, see, it is a string. Now, let's say, guys, if I wanted to load it as a JSON object, so what I'll do, I will import the JSON, then I'll write over here JSON.
Sunny: load.
Sunny: Underscore.
Sunny: loads, right? Now here, guys, I will be passing this particular detail. Now, if I'm going to be executed, guys, now see.
Sunny: Now, this is not a dictionary… now there's not a string. It is a JSON object.
Sunny: What it is, it is a JSON object. Clear, guys, tell me yes or no.
Sunny: You can check it out, you can pass it in the type.
Sunny: You can check it out, this one. So, it is a dict. Means, it is a JSON only, right? So, either in the python… in the python that JSON only, it's a dict. Got it?
Sunny: The JSON object only, it is a dict only. Got it?
Sunny: So we can convert that string into where? We can convert that string into the JSON object, or you can say in Adict. I hope this is clear.
Sunny: Tell me, guys, if it is KAL or not.
Sunny: Now, guys, let's, call something else over here. So, we have a user, guys. See, this is my user.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: User is what? User is a class. Now, on top of this user, I can call one more method. So, I can call over here model underscore validate.
Sunny: Okay? Moder is underscore validate. Now, guys, let's say you are getting data from somewhere. Now, you wanted to validate the data, right? You wanted to validate data. Now, tell me, this is a class, guys, this is a schema. Tell me, yes or no.
Sunny: Is it a schema or not? Is this a schema? So this is what… this is a schema. Now, here, what I'm doing, guys, I'm going to be initialize this as schema.
Sunny: Okay, I'm going to be initialize this schema. If it is not meeting to the structure, or value, or data type, or whatever, it will throw the error, right? But guys, just think, against this schema, if I wanted to validate something.
Sunny: Against this schema, if I wanted to validate something. Let me copy this schema over here, this one.
Sunny: Okay, so against this particular schema, guys, now let's say if I wanted to validate something, if I'm getting a data from somewhere, let's say I'm getting a data, this data.
Sunny: Okay, and if I wanted to, validate this one, Against the…
Sunny: a schema. So what I'll do, guys, I'll use this class.
Sunny: And on top of it, I'll call one method.
Sunny: model.
Sunny: validate, and I'll pass the data. If it is meeting the requirement, if this data actually is meeting the requirement of this schema, so it will run it, okay? See.
Sunny: It will not give me any sort of an error.
Sunny: Getting my point? So, using this method, we can directly validate our data. If we're getting our data from somewhere, we can directly validate that.
Sunny: The one way, basically, we have a schema, we can initialize it.
Sunny: Okay, so let me initialize it, see?
Sunny: Okay, so here I'm going to be initialized, let's say, the name is Sunny.
Sunny: Age is 30, and city is what? City is the?
Sunny: GOA, right? So, see, we are able to initialize the schema. But guys, let's suppose if we are getting data from somewhere, so directly can we validate the data against this schema? Yes, we can do it.
Sunny: So directly, we can call this method, and we can validate this schema. This functionality is very, very useful inside the AI applications.
Sunny: Understood, guys. Now, let's say instead of this dictionary, we are getting a data in the form of…
Sunny: string, right? If we're getting a data form in the form of a string, right? This one. So, this is what, guys, this is a JSON object, right? Means I can validate using this particular
Sunny: I can validate using this particular method, this one. So, user… user model validation JSON.
Sunny: Now see, guys, so these are data, guys, and we are able to validate this data using this particular method, model validation JSON.
Sunny: Right? Now, guys, here, let's say, this is my… this is my user, right? Now, I wanted to check the user schema in a very, very detail.
Sunny: So what I can do, guys, I can call one method on top of it.
Sunny: The method name is going to be what? Model JSON schema.
Sunny: Okay, see, model varied JSON, this is a different one. Model JSON schema, basically, it will give me the schema, the schema detail of this particular user class. So if I'm going to be run it, guys, see, here you will be getting the complete detail. Are you getting the complete detail?
Sunny: Are you getting the complete detail of this particular user class? Yes or no? So, these methods, actually, you can call just to get the detail, right? Now, we have one more very useful method. See, this is all the functionality I have used in a real time, guys, somewhere.
Sunny: So that's why I'm telling you, because Pydentic is having lots of functionality methods and all. You'll find out, basically, hundreds of methods inside of Pyntic. But what is the useful one? What are the useful ones? So I'm teaching you all the useful methods over here.
Sunny: So, let's say, guys, there's my one user. Can you see one user, guys, over here? Let's say username is Sunny, and the age is 13, okay? This is my user one. Now, can I create a copy of this user? Yes, I can create that. So, here is my user one. I'll call one method on top of it, model underscore.
Sunny: Copy.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And now, guys, this is what this is my user 2.
Sunny: means I can create the copy of the user also. So if I'll show you the user too.
Sunny: So what I'll do, guys, I'll get the copy of it. See? I'm getting a copy of my user. Now, can I update this copy? Yes, I can update this copy. Let's say, here is my user 2.
Sunny: Now, what I'm doing, or let's take a user 1 only. Now, here I'm doing one thing. I'm calling this method.
Sunny: model copy.
Sunny: Okay? And here, guys, I'm passing one parameter.
Sunny: the parameter is going to be update. So whenever we are going to be creating a copy, guys, we can even update the parameter also, okay, while we are creating a copy. Now, let's say what here… who is this, guys? This is my user 3.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: User 3. Okay, guys, if I'll check the detail of the user 3, what I'll be getting, guys, I'll be getting the user 3. See, Sunny, date, and the city is Mumbai. You can update any sort of a parameter, basically.
Sunny: Is it clear?
Sunny: Is this part clear, guys? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: If this part is clear, guys, please let me know in the chat. Now, we have one more thing, guys, see?
Sunny: We have one more thing, one more very, very important concept of the pyntic. That's called the field validator. Okay, so I'm going to teach you two concepts, model validator and the field validator. So, let me import it from the pythonic itself. So, here I'm writing from
Sunny: Okay, model validator and the field validator.
Sunny: So, if we're talking across GitHub Copilot Pro is better, yes, Cloud is better. You can utilize a cloud. Even Copilot is also better, if you wanted something in a cheaper price. Got it, Arvind? Now, guys, here I'm going to create one class. The class name is what, let's say, employ.
Sunny: Now, instead, the employee, guys, tell me how many parameter, how many variables we have.
Sunny: Tell me, guys, how many variables we have inside the employee class. We have two variables, name and the integer.
Sunny: Now, guys, we can put the field validator. Okay, field validator means what? So, instead of writing the field over here, you are writing the field now.
Sunny: So it is having one tack… see, we are having field, right? So we can write the field validator like this, or we can put the… sorry, we can put the field over here, and then, based on the field, basically, we can define the data, sorry, description, metadata, or any sort of a value, whatever we want to… whatever we want to do.
Sunny: Whatever we wanted to get, basically, with respect to this variable.
Sunny: Everything we can define inside the field, or that class, okay?
Sunny: But it is having one more way, field validator, and it is in a more detail, basically. So we can put this decorator, field validator, and we can put the, basically some, checks on top of this name, okay? So how we can do that? So here, basically, we are going to be define one class method.
Sunny: So, let me define the class method. Now, under this class method, basically, we can define one function, validateName, okay? So, it will take a value, actually, and it will check the name, right? It will check the length, actually, right? Length of the…
Sunny: name. So, here is the logic of it.
Sunny: If it is not matching, okay, length is not matching, guys, then what it will do, it will raise the value error, okay? If the length of the name is not matching, what it will do, guys, it will raise the value error. Otherwise, what it will do, guys, it will return the title of the value.
Sunny: So, this type of, validation also we can do. There is one more, like, specific decorator, field validator, okay? Let me execute it, and I can check it now. So, tell me, guys, whether this will work or not.
Sunny: Whether this will work or not.
Sunny: Field validator, basically, it is… field validator is for what? Field validator, basically, it is put some custom logic on top of the parameter, okay?
Sunny: Otherwise, we have a field class, you can initialize that, but again, if you wanted to put some custom logic, you can write in this particular manner, right? Now here, guys, you can see employees Sunny and 13. If I'm going to be executed, it will work.
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, whether this will work or not, if I'm going to be initialize it like this.
Sunny: If I'm going to be initialize the class like this, This one.
Sunny: Tell me, is it going to work or not?
Sunny: Value. Title means, basically, it will provide me the specific value of that, valued, okay? Don't return the title, return the value only, so it will… having some meta… it will be having some metadata. If I'm going to be executed… see, guys, it is giving me the error.
Sunny: So, it is very, very useful now whenever we are checking the password length or something, correct?
Sunny: It is very, very important now, whenever we are checking the password length or something, correct? In that case. Now, guys, we have one more thing, that is what? That is a model validator, okay? So, it's doing the same kind of thing, let me show you that. So, here, guys, you can see…
Sunny: This is the class, guys. Now, can you see this class? Is it clearly visible to all of you?
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, what we are doing inside this class.
Sunny: If you are able to understand that, please let me know. So, we have a password, and then we have a confirm password to field. Then we have a model validator, and here mode is after. Okay, later on, I'll check. After the initialization, basically, I'll check that.
Sunny: So, here, guys, what I'll do, I'll check that, okay, after the initialization. Now, check password. So, what I'm checking, guys, so here, basically, I'm checking. Now, let me define it one more time, just a second.
Sunny: So what I'm checking, guys, I'm checking if password is not equal to the confirmed password, so I'm raising the value error, otherwise I'm returning this self. Okay, self means what? It is going to be point out to this particular object only. Let me execute it, and here, if I'm going to be initialize it like this, sign up, now see?
Sunny: It is… it is able to initialize, okay?
Sunny: But guys, let's see if I'm going to be initialize it like this. This one.
Sunny: Now, tell me, guys, whether it will work or it will, give me the error.
Sunny: Tell me fast.
Sunny: I just wanted to, like, let this know, so whether it will work or it will run it.
Sunny: It will not run, because password is not matching, right? So if I'm running it, guys, see, it is showing me the validation error.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: So, what is the differences between this field validator and the model validator?
Sunny: What are the differences?
Sunny: Okay. So, the difference is very, very easy. So, here you can see the differences, guys. So, field validator basically is working on the one field.
Sunny: Right? Field validator. Only one field, one parameter. Now, if we're talking about the model validator, guys, who is working on the entire model?
Sunny: Okay, multiple fields, whole object. So that's why it is able to understand the password and the confirmed password, these two parameters all together.
Sunny: So this is the differences between the field validator and the model validator. Is it getting clear?
Sunny: Yes or no?
Sunny: Mode after means what later on is going to be check the value. You can understand in the… in this way.
Sunny: We are getting the complete model, actually. After initializing the value, we are getting the complete model. And on top of it, we are going to be implement the validation.
Sunny: Okay? I kept, some differences in the notepad, let me keep it over here, see? This one.
Sunny: So, field validator, validate a single field, validate a multiple field. Work on an individual field value, work on a complete object model.
Sunny: Is it clear, guys? Tell me yes or no?
Sunny: One sign-up object inside for the first time. Yes, correct.
Sunny: Class method is not required over here.
Sunny: This one. If you wanted to mention, you can.
Sunny: But that is basically required inside the field validator, okay, whenever we are working with a single field.
Sunny: Generally, in the model validation, it is not required.
Sunny: In the field validator, it is required.
Sunny: Okay? Model validator, actually, it is validating the both thing. This both value, password and the confirmed password.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Okay, now let's do one thing, guys, let's understand one more concept of the pythic, which is very useful. And then, guys, I will stop, sorry, I will close this python one, sorry, pyntic one, okay? Because, like, those many concepts, these many concepts are the enough one for building any sort of a application.
Sunny: So, guys, now, guys, we are going to be understand about what? We are going to be understanding about the nested schema.
Sunny: So, can we create the nested schema? Is it possible inside the pyntic? This is also very useful when I was working in one of the real-time projects. So, there we have created so many nested schema, okay? So, again, I kept this particular concept. Now, see over here.
Sunny: how we can validate this nested schema, how we can create that. So, we have a user. Inside the user, we have name, age, and email. Now, we have address. Now, inside the address, we have city, state, and PIN code. Now, inside the, basically, the user basically is belonging to the company. Now, in the company, basically, we have company name and the department.
Sunny: So, can we create this kind of schema in the python tank? What do you think, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: Yes? Okay. So, first, let's create the address, first, let's create the address one. So, this is the address, guys. Now, see, in the address, what we have, we have a city, state, and the PIN code.
Sunny: Okay? So this is my first schema. Now, guys, what I'm doing, I'm going to create another schema that's going to be a company schema, right? So here is my company schema.
Sunny: Now, guys, let's say if I wanted to create the user schema, how I can create the user schema?
Sunny: This is the important thing. So if you'll look into the user schema, so inside that, we will be having the name, age, and email. This is fine, guys, but apart from this one, we are having two more things.
Sunny: Okay, we have two more things. The another one, basically, is what? Address, and the next one is what? Next one is the company.
Sunny: So, address type is this address, this one, and the company type is this company. Is it getting killer, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: Is it getting clear to all of you?
Sunny: So, it's like what? It's like a nested schema. If I wanted to create this schema, how I can create that, how I can validate that? So, let's suppose if you have this kind of data.
Sunny: If you have this kind of data, guys, what kind of data? Let me show you the data. Just a second.
Sunny: I'm giving you the data, guys, just a second. Let me take it from my notepad, I capped it.
Sunny: So, this is the data, guys, this one.
Sunny: user data. Now, guys, tell me, can we validate this particular data? Name is Sunny, age is this one, email is this one, address is this one, PIN code, company is ABC technology, and department is AI engineering.
Sunny: So, can we validate this particular data against this schema? Now, here, guys, what I'm doing, guys, tell me. Here, I'm going to be called… here, I'm basically taking this user.
Sunny: And then, guys, I'm calling one method, model.
Sunny: validate. And here, basically, I'm passing what? I'm passing the user data. Okay? I am passing what?
Sunny: I'm passing user underscore data. Now, see guys, are we able to validate this data successfully?
Sunny: Are we able to validate this data? Now, guys, instead of the validation, let's say, if I wanted to initialize this object, can we initialize this object? Yes, we can initialize this object. That is also possible over here. So, how to initialize this object, guys? This user object? Now, see, guys, this is the user initialization.
Sunny: Okay, so, user object initialization, so let me, basically keep it over here, see. Name, Sunny, age is this one, email is this one, address, and the company. If you want to run it, guys, see, we are getting this particular schema.
Sunny: Is it getting clear how to create an SRed schema? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: How many people are able to understand this entire pandemic?
Sunny: Are we good to, are we good to go with a python concept? If we are good to go with this python concept, then, please let me know in the chat. And these many concepts are the enough one for any sort of a practical, okay? So, guys, please practice with this particular notebook, it's an important one.
Sunny: And it's having so many things, once you will practice with this, particular notebook.
Sunny: Really, guys, you will have a… you will have a good understanding of the python tank.
Sunny: It's having lots of, function in the functionality. So, can I, show you one notebook, guys? You can use this particular notebook as a reference when it is having, almost 194 functionality of the Pydentic. I created it during my, like, this,
Sunny: material creation and all from the, documentation itself. So, this is the notebook, guys, this one.
Sunny: So, just look into the functionality. It is having around 194 cell.
Sunny: Okay. I hope it is visible, guys. Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: So, whatever functionality could be possible inside the Pyntic, I capped everything. It is not possible to cover inside the live class, but yeah, I created from the… I created from the Pyntic documentation itself.
Sunny: so many different, different concepts of Pydentic. Nothing, basically, will go out of this Pydentic one. Even you don't require this much of understanding of the Pydentic. Most of the understanding I already given inside this IP1B file. But yeah, I can share this one. So, guys, tell me, should I share it or not?
Sunny: I can share it over here, so just look into this notebook.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, how's the session so far? I hope you liked it.
Sunny: Now, I'm giving you this entire changes.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so I can post these changes to the GitHub.
Sunny: Great.
Sunny: So yeah, this is it in a pydentic. Now, let's do one thing, guys. Let's start with the Langraf memory. Let's take a quick break, 5 minutes of broader break. Then we'll start with the Langrah memory. We'll understand all the concept, like, thread and all, checkpointing in the memory as well. So today and tomorrow, we'll discuss two concepts. One is the Langraf memory.
Sunny: And another one is going to be, human in loop, okay? So, those concepts, we are going to be understanding. Then, the rest of the concept, we are going to be discussing the upcoming classes. So, Lang Graph, orchestration, okay, SAN API, subgraph concept and all. So, in the upcoming class, we'll discuss.
Sunny: So fine, guys, let's take a quick break, a water break, then we'll start with a new concept.
Sunny: Thank you guys, we'll start after 5 minutes, with the Lang Rav Memory. Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, guys, I think we can start the session. I hope everyone is there.
Sunny: So, guys, today I'm not going to be… conclude this memory part, so that, we'll do in the next session, okay? There are so many things, basically, which I have to be discussed.
Sunny: With respect to this memory, Langraph Memory and all. So today, we'll just, understand, this, memory, Langraph Memory part with one small example.
Sunny: And, then, we'll, come… we'll, basically complete it in tomorrow's session. So tomorrow, guys, I will show you, different, different, example.
Sunny: And, I will show you how you can, get… how you can basically, save the memory in, one database, and how you can retrieve it from there, okay? So, everything we are going to be discussed in tomorrow's class.
Sunny: So, let's start, with the Langraph Memory. So, are you ready, guys? Let me create a new notebook over here.
Sunny: Memory and Langraph.
Sunny: dot IPvy.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, guys, I will select the kernel first, so let me select the kernel.
Sunny: Here's the code. Now, here I'm going to write print, all.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Hi, so this is working fine. Now, guys, what I'll do…
Sunny: I will start, writing up code. So, Langraph, basically, it is, supporting so many things with respect to this memory and all. So, guys, today, we'll take a look onto some sort of a concept, okay?
Sunny: So, let's do one thing, guys. Let's, basically implement something. So, first of all, you should have Langraph inside your, current virtual environment.
Sunny: Then there is some input statement, which I'm going to be right over here, so just focus.
Sunny: The first is a UUID, this is just to provide the unique ID. Then a data class is there, then init chat model is there, just to initialize the chat model, okay?
Sunny: Then, state graph, messages, state, start, and I think you're already familiar with this particular, function, this particular methods, okay, this particular classes. Then, in Memory Saver.
Sunny: So, checkpointing also we can save in memory, and basically, memory also we can store in the… in memory, okay, in the runtime.
Sunny: So tomorrow, guys, I'll show you how you can process this memory inside the database. So, let me execute it, and I hope this is clear.
Sunny: What I'm doing, guys, so here, guys, I'm going to be initialize the model. So, this is my simple method. Init chat model. So, I can directly import it from the Langraph, sorry, from the LangChat. And whichever model I wanted to import, sorry, whichever model I wanted to use, I just have to be past the model name over here.
Sunny: And then I can initialize the model. Got it? So, now let me do one thing. So my model is there.
Sunny: Now, what I'll do, guys, I will create a checkpointer. So this checkpointer basically is for what?
Sunny: This is for the, sorry, this, in-memory object, in-memory saber object is for what? This is just for the checkpoint, okay? For, like, storing the…
Sunny: conversation history for the particular thread, okay, for the particular thread ID. So, this is my one of the checkpointers. Now, guys, again, I'm going to create one more checkpointer.
Sunny: Sorry, again, I'm going to create one more object of this in memory. So this is from the… this is the store, actually, right? So this is for the, user-specific information across all the thread. Getting my point.
Sunny: So let me do one thing, let me cut it down from here, let me keep it over here. So this is, like, one more in memory. I can…
Sunny: keep the in-memory. Both, method name is the in-memory.
Sunny: And here, this in memory, basically, it's a…
Sunny: in-memory… sorry, in-memory saver, in-memory store. So, this in-memory store, basically, it is for saving the…
Sunny: like, the long-term memory, okay? Long-term memory across the conversation with respect to the particular user. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So I hope this part is clear. Tell me yes or no. Is it getting killer, these two glasses?
Sunny: If it is clear, guys, you can let me know inside the chat, so that we can proceed. And even I can write this particular import statement over here, inside the cell, so that you will have a clear-cut understanding. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So, this is fine. Now, this is my chat model.
Sunny: Okay, this is my in-memory saver for the checkpointer, and this is my in-memory store for the longer memory, okay? For the long-running memory. Everything, guys, I'll discuss, this is just a warm-up class for the memory.
Sunny: So, if you know my teaching style, then please believe on me, guys. Everything will be clarified with respect to the memory. This is just a warm-up session, so that, you can look into the code, the… look into the code of the memory, like, how it looks like.
Sunny: Okay? And, then, guys,
Sunny: We'll discuss so many examples, and I will give you the, different, different code-related explanation. Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Yes? Okay, great. So if you trust on me, guys, just follow to me, and I believe you, I give you that, like, belief, then everything is going to be clear with respect to the memory, okay?
Sunny: Yes, concept will also be clear money. Concept will also be clear with respect to this memory. So, without the concept, I will, not execute this code. Got it? So, here, guys, what we have? We have a data class. So, let me define the data class.
Sunny: Nope.
Sunny: Why we define the data class, can anyone tell me?
Sunny: So, why we define this data class?
Sunny: Data class is simple. Again, it is a schema only, okay? So, we can utilize this user ID from this context class. So, let me do one thing, let me write the context.underscore user ID, okay?
Sunny: user underscore IT. Now, see, guys.
Sunny: it is giving me the error, because we have not initialized it so far, no? So, we can initialize the user ID, let's say this, my user ID. If you will check the user ID, so you will get the user ID, okay?
Sunny: So this is the user ID, which we have initialized over here.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So, again, it is kind of a schema. Okay, using the data class again, we can create the schema, right? So, I hope this part is clear. Now, what I'm doing, guys, so I'm going to create one node over here.
Sunny: So what this node is doing… so let me define the node.
Sunny: The node name is the assistant node.
Sunny: Okay, now it's taking two things. One is the state, and the second is what? Second is the runtime.
Sunny: Got it, guys. Now, what I'll do, guys, I will take the…
Sunny: user ID, the current user ID, Okay.
Sunny: Then, guys, after that, I will be defining the namespace, right? So, what is this namespace and all everything, guys, I'll be discussing this namespace, where we have a user, user ID, and the memories.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, this is my user… user ID and the memories. So, what we have, guys, we have a namespace.
Sunny: Just be, foc- just focused over here, okay? Everything you will be getting, guys, don't worry, every sort of a concept.
Sunny: I'll explain you. So one is a user ID, and another one is a namespace. Now, what I'll do, guys, I'll take the latest message of the user. So, let me take the latest message of the user from the state.
Sunny: So this is the latest message from the user.
Sunny: Now, guys, here, I'm going to be… define one condition.
Sunny: the condition is going to be what? So the condition, basically, if user message, Start with remember.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So what I'm doing, guys, from there, remember, we are going to be…
Sunny: extract the memory, this one. User message, length of remember, okay? Then, guys, what we are getting, we are getting the memory.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, what I'm doing… so, in the runtime itself, we are going to be put this memory.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So the runtime itself, we are going to be put this memory. So, where we are going to be put it? So, we are going to be put it inside our store, right? So, runtime.restore.put.
Sunny: Now, here what I'm doing, guys, so this is my nam space.
Sunny: Here is my… User ID.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Or let it be like this only.
Sunny: So here is my namespace, UUID, and the data. So as of now, I'm showing you how we can handle this particular thing inside the Langraph, right? I have a code inside my notepad, so I'm, keep writing it over here. Now, guys, what I'll do, guys, I'll…
Sunny: print this thing. So let me print this particular thing, okay, just to get the detail over the…
Sunny: Just to get the detail over the… where, guys?
Sunny: Just to get the detail over the console. Got it? So, I hope this is clear, guys. Now, what I'm doing, guys, for the runtime, for the long-term memory also, I'm going to be perform… I'm going to be, like, write something over here.
Sunny: So what I have, guys, I have this runtime. Let me… Right over here.
Sunny: This one?
Sunny: So, we have this memory runtime.store.search. So, what I'll be getting, I'll be getting the memories, actually, right? So, it is for the longer run.
Sunny: It is for the longer run, and this particular thing is going to be out of this.
Sunny: Out of this if condition, okay? As of now, if you're not getting anything, guys, don't worry, I will explain each and every line, this is my promise to all of you, okay? Just believe on me, everything will be clarified.
Sunny: Now here, guys, we are having the memory text, so let me keep the memory text over here.
Sunny: So, this is a memory text.
Sunny: Okay? So, from where we are getting, we are getting it from the memories. So, this is what is a memory text.
Sunny: And guys, if it is not there, then, basically, we'll raise the error. So here, basically, simply, we can say.
Sunny: What we can say, guys? Let me put it over here.
Sunny: If not memorized, then no saved memory. Got it? So this for the short-term memory, and this for the long-term memory, this one.
Sunny: I hope.
Sunny: This is clear. Now, we are going to be pass everything, we are going to be pass everything, guys, where we are going to be pass everything to the…
Sunny: LLM. So for that, we have one system prompt.
Sunny: So let me define one system prompt.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, here is what, guys? Here is my system prompt. This what?
Sunny: There's my system prompt.
Sunny: Got it, guys? So, just read the system prompt, what I'm doing over here. So, you are a helpful assistant.
Sunny: Okay, long-term memories about this user, so there's a memory text, this one.
Sunny: Then, guys, what we have… this is what? This is my…
Sunny: Here, basically, I have defined the… Sorry, here, basically, I'm calling the model, model.invoke.
Sunny: So, role is a system, system prompt, and then we'll be having the message over here. Got it? So, what I'll be getting, guys, I'll be getting the response
Sunny: Okay? And then finally, I'm going to be written this particular response. So this is a simple node which I have defined.
Sunny: Just to capture the memory. Understood, guys? How many of you are able to understand? Maybe, you're not able to get this entire thing. Until and unless I will give you the explanation of this entire code.
Sunny: So once this entire code is going to be clarif- like, clarified, right, this will become very, very simple for all of you, right?
Sunny: So, I hope this is clear. Here is what, here is my written statement.
Sunny: Now, what I'll do, guys, so here, I will, basically create a graph. So, let me create a graph. So, here, I will, initialize a graph state graph, I'm passing the state, and now I'm passing the context also, right? So, here, if you will see the context, guys, so this is what is my context.
Sunny: I have created a class now, this one. This one. This one. User ID, right? So that is what, that's my context. Now, what I'll do, guys, I'll create my builder.
Sunny: I'll add the node over here. So, here is my assistant.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Let me add the notes. So, this is my assistant, guys, this one.
Sunny: Then what I have, I have the start node and the end node. Both nodes is also there, let me add it over here.
Sunny: So one is the start node, and the other node is the end node.
Sunny: Now, what I'm doing, guys, I'm just going to be compile this graph. So, here is my builder.
Sunny: Then what I'll do, guys, I will simply pass the check pointer, okay, and the store. There's two things I'm going to be passed while I'm going to be compiling.
Sunny: So here, guys, you can see my graph is ready.
Sunny: Okay? Now, what I'll do, guys, I will define one method.
Sunny: So the method basically is responsible to provide the detail of the message.
Sunny: This is a very simple method. If you'll read it out, you will get it. So we have a message, user ID, and the thread ID. Okay? So here, we are going to invoke the graph with a user message.
Sunny: Now, here is what? Here's my configuration, thread ID, and the user ID. We're getting our answer, and we are going to be written that particular answer.
Sunny: Understood, guys? Now tell me how many of you are able to understand this code.
Sunny: How many of you are able to understand this particular code? Maybe you got some sort of an idea on a high level, but
Sunny: most of you, you are not getting anything out of this code, right? So this is, like, one of the ways of sustaining the memory inside Ver inside the Langra.
Sunny: This is one of the code, basically. It's… you will get this particular code inside the, latest version of the Langraph, right? So today, I will just stick with this code. Tomorrow, guys, I will discuss all the theoretical point, what is a memory, how to keep that, what is this, that, everything we are going to be discussed with respect to the memory, right?
Sunny: Oh, guys, first of all, let me explain you something.
Sunny: Okay. Let me explain you something, guys, so that your understanding will be clear over here.
Sunny: My word is visible, just let me know in the chat if it is visible.
Sunny: Ajit, what is the meaning of the memory?
Sunny: What's the meaning of the memory in context of this AI application?
Sunny: So let's say if I'm writing over here, memory.
Sunny: So, can I say… It is a shared history.
Sunny: Yes or no, guys, tell me.
Sunny: There's a chat history, yes or no? Okay. Now, guys, how we can design this memory inside the LAN graph, right?
Sunny: So, see.
Sunny: We are having two things.
Sunny: The one is called the user ID.
Sunny: And the second is called what? Second is called the thread ID.
Sunny: thread ID.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, user ID means what? User ID, basically, it is… Discriminating between the user, okay?
Sunny: So… user ID, basically, it's an ID to the specific user. So let's say here I'm chatting.
Sunny: then my ID, let's say 123.
Sunny: Now, another one is chatting. Let's say Rahul is chatting.
Sunny: So let's say this is the ID for the Rahul. Let's say some other person is chatting, let's say Ankit is chatting.
Sunny: So this is the ID of the Ankit.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Thread ID, now there could be thread ID also.
Sunny: So…
Sunny: something like this. Whatever, basically, thread ID could be there. ABC, BCD, any UUID, right? Any sort of a, like, thread ID could be there, right? So there is a two thing. One is a user ID, and another one is the thread ID.
Sunny: Now, guys, let's say there is a user. The username is what? Username is Sunny.
Sunny: Now, guys, this Sunny, actually, it can initiate a lot of threat.
Sunny: thread. Let's say thread 1.
Sunny: Thread 1.
Sunny: Okay, thread what? Thread 1. So, with respect to this thread 1, I will be having one thread ID.
Sunny: Now, thread 2.
Sunny: No, thread 3.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, corresponding to this thread 2 and thread 3 also, I'll be having some ID. You can think this particular scenario using the Chad GPT, right? So, let's say I have a chat GPT,
Sunny: My user is there, right? Sunny Savita is there.
Sunny: ChatGPT, I have logged in over the Chatt. Now, over the ChatGPT, what I can do, I can initiate so many chats, new chats.
Sunny: Let's say this is the new chatt one.
Sunny: Let's say this is the new chatt tool.
Sunny: This is a new check.
Sunny: 3.
Sunny: So, this every chat, actually, it is associated with thread ID.
Sunny: 1?
Sunny: thread ID.
Sunny: Understood, guys, tell me, yes or no.
Sunny: It's a parallel chat thread.
Sunny: Okay. So, multiple chat thread, basically, I can initiate over the chat GPT, either me, yes or no, guys. Is it possible or not?
Sunny: Right? Now, let's say in one thread, in one chat, in one chat, what I'm doing, let's say I'm going to be discuss about the lank, I'm going to be discuss about the machine learning.
Sunny: In another chat, basically, I'm going to be discuss about what?
Sunny: Let's say in another chat, I'm going to be discussing about the generative AI.
Sunny: Let's say in another chat, I'm going to be discussing about the DSA.
Sunny: Okay? So, I'm… I have initialized 3 parallel chat, I've initialized 3 chat, okay? In a different, different thread, in a different, different chat, my different, different chatting is there. My different, different history is there. So, with respect to one user, there could be multiple thread.
Sunny: And you can understand this thing in this way. Thread ID, thread ID would be there, so with every sort of a chat, with every sort of a new chat, one thread ID will be associated. Making sense to all of you? Yes or no? Now, we have a user-level isolation also.
Sunny: We have a user-level isolation also. Now, let's say we have two users.
Sunny: Raza there is a… Sunny123.
Sunny: Oh, here is a Rahul.
Sunny: 1, 2, 3, okay? Now, the study, basically.
Sunny: Right? It can run the multiple charts, multiple thread.
Sunny: And Rahul also can run the multiple chats, multiple thread.
Sunny: So this user and this thread, actually, we can easily mention.
Sunny: this user… And this thread, That's a thread one.
Sunny: Thread 2…
Sunny: Thread 3, thread 1, thread 2, Thread 3, right? So this user and this cha… and this thread, basically, easily we can mention… easily we can maintain inside the LAN grav.
Sunny: And this is one of the ways…
Sunny: And this is one of the ways, basically, to… Manage the chat history.
Sunny: That is also called a memory.
Sunny: Now, if you are talking on the memory, right, so somewhere will have to be saved. So tell me, guys, where we are saving this memory?
Sunny: So, as of now, we are saving this particular memory in… In memory, right?
Sunny: In memory, basically, it's the RAM.
Sunny: volatile memory.
Sunny: So it's not a permanent. If the session is going to be destroyed, then this memories also be erased.
Sunny: So, if you want a persistent memory.
Sunny: then we'll have to keep this particular memory inside some DB.
Sunny: So tomorrow, I'll show you how you can configure even the post gray, right? You can configure the SQLite.
Sunny: Any sort of a database you can configure to keep the memory. Understood, guys? Yes or no? Tell me, is it getting cleared to all of you?
Sunny: Tell me.
Sunny: So today, basically, I have shown you the class, the in-memory class. Don't worry, just a glimpse, actually, of the Langraph Memory Management at all. We can understand this thing in a very detail.
Sunny: So, the initial doubt is clear.
Sunny: If the initial doubt is clear, I think we can, run this code and we can check whether everything is working fine or not. And don't worry, guys, tomorrow.
Sunny: I will explain you everything from scratch. Today, I will stop the session here. I don't want to be overwhelmed this session, so tomorrow, again, I will start from here itself. Got it?
Sunny: Great.
Sunny: Okay, so let me execute it again, so that you can look over here. So this is my model, this is my in-memory saver, checkpointer.
Sunny: Okay, then there's my store. Now, what is the difference between the checkpointer and the store, guys?
Sunny: Anyone know, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: If someone is no, you can let me know. Checkpointer, basically, we are…
Sunny: keeping the… we are storing the conversation, right? We are storing the thread, right? User… and store means what? Store means? User-specific long-term memory.
Sunny: Okay, checkpointer means what? It's a snapshot.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It is what it's a?
Sunny: snapshot, basically.
Sunny: Check pointer, what it is doing is just taking the snapshot of the memory, and the store, basically, it is taking the complete history of the conversation.
Sunny: So, checkpointer, remember the conversation, while store, remember the user across the conversation.
Sunny: Okay, so tomorrow, again, I will be clarifying this one. So let me do one thing, guys. Let me, execute it in Memory Saver.
Sunny: Now, here in… we are going to be… store the checkpointer. Now, in memory store, we are going to be stored the memory. This is my, like, user ID. Here, I define how to, like, get it. Now, it is taking run… state and runtime.
Sunny: Right? From just, like, taking the message, and it's taking the context from the runtime. Now, this is my entire code, guys. Tomorrow, I'll discuss this code again. As of now, let's execute it.
Sunny: So, here is my state, there's my node, here's my edges, here is my, graph.
Sunny: Now, this is my chat method, okay, which is taking message, user ID, thread ID. If I want to test it, guys, how I can test it?
Sunny: If I want to test it, how I get tested. So the testing is also very, very easy.
Sunny: Okay, I just need to be called what? I just need to be called this chat method.
Sunny: So let me call this chat method, and for that, guys, again, I have some example.
Sunny: So, let's say there's my chart method. See, this one.
Sunny: So, I'm passing… I'm saying, what is my current project? Okay, so directly I'm, like, asking what is my current project? So, this… this could be a follow-up question. So here, what I'm doing, guys, here, before that, I'm going to define one more question.
Sunny: My current project is an Agentic rag. There's a user ID, Sunny123, and then there is a thread ID, okay?
Sunny: So, here, guys, what I'm doing, I'm going to be executed. Once I'll execute, guys, you will see the complete detail over here.
Sunny: So, you'll see the message, see user message, assistant, okay? What assistant is saying. Now, what I'm doing, guys, again, I'm going to be executing this one. Now, what is my current project with respect to the same thread?
Sunny: Right? So whenever you are talking with the Chad GPT, so in a backend, it is also working in the same way. It is assigning user ID and the thread ID to the specific user and message. Got it?
Sunny: So, here, guys, if I'm executing enough, see. So, user is asking, user, what is my current project? So, assistant is saying, your current project is a rag, right?
Sunny: So we can, basically, ask the follow-up question. Got it?
Sunny: Now, what we can do, we can, basically, initialize a different, different thread also. We can initialize a different, different, what I can do, different, different, basically, user also. Okay, so let me do one thing, let me ask one more question over here. So, let's say my question is what?
Sunny: Remember, my first, my favorite programming language is a python. So, this is what is my question. Now, let me run it. So, see. Memory saved.
Sunny: Okay, my favorite programming language is Python. Now, here also, you will see, guys, see,
Sunny: here it is saying my favorite programming language is Python, right? Now, user. User, basically, my favorite programming language. So, assistant is saying, okay, got it, this, this, this, this, right? It is generating in this way. Now, what I'm doing, guys.
Sunny: I'm going to be… initialize a new thread. Okay, let's see whether it is able to, whether it is able to basically answer or not for this particular question.
Sunny: So, here I'm asking, what is my favorite programming language? So, it is saying your favorite programming language is the python. So, I have initialized the second thread, but it's still… it is able to answer for this particular question. Now, tell me why it is able to do that.
Sunny: Because it is not a checkpointer, it is a store. So it is, like, storing a conversation across the threads.
Sunny: Across the different, different threads.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: It is an in-memory store. Now, let me show you how it is working. See, this is the diagram of it. So, we have Sunny123, in-memory store, favorite programming language is Python, thread 1, and thread2, right? So, this in-memory store, basically, it is working across the thread.
Sunny: Okay, across the thread, basically, it is going to be… is store the, detail. Got it?
Sunny: Now, we can basically initialize a different, different, user also. So, let's say, this is my question.
Sunny: This one. Remember, my favorite programming language is python. Okay, so if I'm running it, so that is fine, it is able to.
Sunny: Like, save it, right?
Sunny: Now, over here, guys, what I'm doing… so, let's say the new user is coming. So, here, user is saying… see, I'm passing the different user ID, and the different thread ID also over here.
Sunny: And this is the detail from the user, different user side, right? So, yes, we are able to save the detail of this user also. Which, you can say anything, right? And along with that, if the suffix is remembered, then it will be able to store this detail in the
Sunny: long memory, right? In the… basically, in the database, right? The in-memory store, right? So it is working in this particular manner. Now, see, user is there, favorite programming is python, favorite programming language is Java, right? So now, what you can do, guys, you can…
Sunny: Any slice up one more thread over here. So here you can see what is my favorite programming language. Rahul is this one, there's a user ID 456 over here, and there's a second thread.
Sunny: Okay, so if you will ask the same question from this particular thread, it still will be able to answer. Why?
Sunny: Because it is going to be… sustain the memory, the complete memory, because we are putting this particular suffix, it is going to be append. See, whenever we are working with a Chatt and all that, again, we… it is not, like, visible to us, but in a backend, something is this… something, this kind of thing is being attached, maybe, in a backend, okay? So this is one of the logic, basically, which we can implement.
Sunny: Tomorrow, guys, I will clarify more about it, because I have to explain about the basics of the memory. So, tomorrow I'll take a couple of more examples from basics, not the Langrav from the basic one, and definitely I'll be discussing that.
Sunny: Memory itself, okay? What is a memory, and how does it work? Getting my point, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Tell me yes. So, if you wanted to check the detail of the memory.
Sunny: Okay, so how you can check? So let's say this is a user ID. This is the user ID, 123. What you can do, guys? You can…
Sunny: define into the namespace, and then you can iterate over the namespace, guys, that's it. So once you iterate over the namespace, you will be getting the complete memory of that, right? So whatever, like, chat we had related to that specific, user ID and the thread ID, you will be getting the complete detail, like this.
Sunny: Getting my point, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: I hope, you are able to get it. You can even execute in this particular manner also, and definitely, you will be getting the answer, this one.
Sunny: So today, guys, I'm not going to be discussing anything more with respect to memory. There's one of the single file, which I'm providing you, so just focus over here. Tomorrow, guys, I will start this memory from scratch.
Sunny: And, I will explain to you a couple of more concepts apart from this length graph. Today, I have not done that.
Sunny: Okay, so I have just give you… I have just given you the glimpse of this, Langraph code.
Sunny: Right? So tomorrow, guys, we have a detailed session of the memory, as well as human in the loop, right? So both things we are going to be discussed. So, I would request you please go through with this entire file right now, take a look what we have done over here, understand the logic and all, and tomorrow, again, we'll start from here itself. Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Tell me, is it getting killer to all of you?
Sunny: Yes, definitely, Abhi Shaikh. I'll be re-explaining this entire thing, because I know, you have so many doubts, so many things, yet to discuss. It's just a glimpse from the Langra, but yeah, I have to discuss the memory concept from the starting.
Sunny: Got it? So, definitely, I'll do that.
Sunny: Okay, so please go through with this entire code and all. Today, I'm not going to discuss any more, thing. I'm just leaving it for tomorrow.
Sunny: And, yeah, tomorrow we'll, go ahead with this one. So, did you get a code, guys? Just give me a quick confirmation in the chat if you got a code.
Sunny: Here, we don't have anything, I just explained you over the one page itself.
Sunny: So if you got the code, just give me quick thumbs up so that I can…
Sunny: Go ahead with the doubt session, okay? So, let me, conclude the session, guys.
Sunny: Let's discuss the remaining thing in the next class. So, here is the code. Remember in the line graph, just check it out, this one. This is the pydentic one, and this is the pyntic, a shorter version, which we have discussed in the today… which we have discussed in today's class.
Sunny: So, fine, guys, I hope you liked the session. Tell me if you like the session, then please give me a quick thumbs up. And tomorrow, guys, don't miss tomorrow's session, it's going to be very important, because the same thing, basically, we are going to be using our Converse Session AI, project, okay? So…
Sunny: what we can do, guys, I can, show you one practical use case with a conversational AI, and there we can, implement this entire memory and all. See, memory concept is not required everywhere.
Sunny: Okay, it is required in the conversational AI, it is required in the chatbot, it is required in the QA system and all, that's it. So, in every AI use case, this memory concept is not required. If you're simply going to be generate some report, if you're simply going to be reviewing anything using the LLM,
Sunny: Okay, if you're going to create those kind of applications, then… Memory concept is not useful.
Sunny: It is useful when?
Sunny: you are making some conversational system. Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: Is there any validity of the memory? Yes, there could be validity of the memory. We can put those checks in the constraint. Got it?
Sunny: AI coding Agent is also a good choice nowadays, which can generate a code in a…
Sunny: Runtime itself, and it can understand the business acquiring the runtime, and it can generate the code as well, and it can integrate it inside the current code base, the current pipeline.
Sunny: I have seen many companies are, working on the, like, the coding agent, okay? They are putting much effort on the coding agent. What that coding agent is doing, you know?
Sunny: They have a system. Now the new requirement is coming.
Sunny: that coding agent will be activated. Automatically, it will create a code, it will test that, it will integrate inside the pipeline, and then our feature is done. That's it. Okay.
Sunny: So, that kind of thing, like, is happening. Have you used the clod skills?
Sunny: Tell me, guys.
Sunny: So, in the Cloud Skill Sol Sona.
Sunny: the same kind of thing. Automatically generate the code, automatically generate the script, actually.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: I will show you the clod script, sorry, clod skills. It's a very useful, and a very important, and a very good feat, good, basically.
Sunny: feature of the cloud. Okay, so definitely we are going to be discussing that.
Sunny: Dude?
Sunny: So, now, let's do one thing, guys. Let's,
Sunny: conclude this session. Tomorrow, again, we'll start from here itself. Until thank you, bye, take care. If you have any sort of a doubt, be here. I will take a doubt session. Thank you very much.
Sunny: Bye, take care.
Sunny: Putting a timer for 2 minutes, then we'll start again.
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: Thank you. Bye.
Sunny: Okay, guys, let's start with the doubt session. If you have any sort of a doubt, you can…
Sunny: Raise your hand.
Sunny: What's a doubt.
raghu.pr: Sunil, am I audible?
Sunny: Yes, you are audible.
raghu.pr: First of all, happy to just say.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, thank you very much, Rubu.
raghu.pr: Basically, I'm building an internal chatbot platform.
Sunny: Use… Mom?
raghu.pr: create React agent, basic tool, tool calling agent only.
raghu.pr: Okay, it has around 30 tools bound to it, like, for search, create, update work items, PID decomposition.
raghu.pr: Chart generation, And, like, have you heard of Azure DevOps Bull?
Sunny: Azure DevOps, yes.
raghu.pr: Yots.
raghu.pr: So, yeah, I am working on that one. The issue is, like, you know, as I add more tools to the agent, the more.
Sunny: That's true.
raghu.pr: I'm saying, like, I have already called the tool, and here is the result, in its response. But when I checked the actual trace, no tool call was ever emitted.
raghu.pr: Like, it's fabricating the, like, you know, like, it is telling the tool, car has been ran, instead of generally invoking it.
raghu.pr: So, yeah, like, what I've noticed is so far from that, like, the toolkit didn't happen.
raghu.pr: And also,
raghu.pr: We previously… I have previously had one issue where the model is, like, fabricating the result without calling the tool call, so how we can validate that? Yeah.
Sunny: You have… sorry, what you have? You have a tool, then?
raghu.pr: Basically, we have a bunch of tools, and I created using Create Triangle.
raghu.pr: Okay?
raghu.pr: So, whenever I'm calling, like, you know, search the work item or update the work item.
raghu.pr: And all. It is simply saying, like, yes, I, like, it will do the reasoning, and it, it is, telling, like, yes, I have created the… I have called the toolcore, and I have got these results.
Sunny: Got it.
raghu.pr: But if I actually go and trace the toolkall, how it has done.
raghu.pr: in there, it never ran a tool call. It is simply taking from the memory, and it is giving the answer.
Sunny: Okay, okay, okay.
raghu.pr: So yeah, like, what I wanted to know is, like, how to, solve this issue.
raghu.pr: Is there a recommended strategy for.
Sunny: You can, put some validator, no, over there, right? Tool call validator, tool result validator. If you're getting those few, I think then you're good to go, right?
raghu.pr: Yes, basically, whenever, like, in the previous chart and all, it has given some answers, right? So, basically, from that memory only, it is fetching and, giving the answer without tooling that tool calling.
Sunny: Got it, I got that point, I got that point clearly. So, on top of that, see, if you don't want to get that answer from the Memory.
raghu.pr: Yes, yes.
Sunny: So, what you can do, you can put some validation. Let's say LLM says, I have… I created some work item.
raghu.pr: Okay.
Sunny: Okay. So, AI message, whatever AI message you are getting, in that, you can specifically check whether the tool call is there or not.
Sunny: Yes or no?
raghu.pr: Yes, see, I have done streaming for reasoning also, so that there only I can see whether it has given the… whether it has done the tool calling or not.
Sunny: Huh. And now, now what you can do, see?
raghu.pr: This one.
Sunny: let's say the tool core is there. Even you have a tool also. Yes. Now.
Sunny: What you can do, you have a matching tool.
Sunny: Now, the tool is being called, and what tool will… what tool will return? It will return the tool message.
raghu.pr: Yes, please.
Sunny: Right? Yes. So… Now you can validate this also. Tool message and tool call, everything you can validate.
Sunny: Okay, so I don't know how you have written the logic, maybe, but yeah, this thing is easy to, like, perform if you know how to…
Sunny: Oh…
Sunny: like, use this line graph and, tool calling feature and all. So, easily you can do that. Got it?
raghu.pr: Okay, basically what I'm learning, I'm trying to implement that.
raghu.pr: Okay, as an internal POC.
raghu.pr: That's what, like, I wanted to get to know about that. Basically, I have done in prompting also, I have, like, strictly enforced it to do the tool calling every… each and time.
raghu.pr: But the model also, you know, sometimes won't, you know, you know, take the, you know, system prompts very clearly and, do the tool calling.
raghu.pr: So, yeah, that's… Well, that's the issue I was facing.
raghu.pr: like, when I give some evaluation, when I try to evaluate, you know, there will I get to know that, yeah, like, probably around… in the long context, whenever the conversation is in long context.
raghu.pr: it used to… the model used to do like that. Without calling the tour calling, it is simply fetching the answer from memory and trying to give. That's the issue.
Sunny: Okay.
raghu.pr: Okay, so…
Sunny: Yeah, do it, and let me know in that next session.
raghu.pr: I will give you the update. Thank you so much.
Sunny: Think.
Sunny: Yeah, Rahul, what's your doubt?
Sunny: Sandeep?
Sunny: What's your doubt?
Sandeep Saboo: Yeah, actually, Sunny.
Sandeep Saboo: It's not just related to this technicals, actually. So, basically, my question is a little broader one. The JCF vehicle,
Sandeep Saboo: you pursue my, GPT Astral launch way, right?
Sandeep Saboo: They are saying that all the coding agents are there, and you know, it automatically does everything.
Sandeep Saboo: And it's a kind of AGI on the horizon, right? So, what do you see, like, all the whole thing going, and how the things are turning in a market?
Sandeep Saboo: In a sense, like, Overall, how the businesses will conduct, how the codes will But it's like,
Sandeep Saboo: Completely taken over by the agents, or you see something that, you know, there will be left for the… you know, this… even the human-in-the-loop concept will go away.
Sandeep Saboo: Because the reasoning and acting, right, as the models become more mature and AGI-oriented.
Sandeep Saboo: So, do you really think that the human in the loop, will, you know, still matter, or it will take decisions on its own?
Sandeep Saboo: So, what is.
Sunny: Yeah, definitely. See, why companies are launching the new model, and they are claiming like this?
Sunny: Because there is a competition in the market, no?
Sunny: If you will see, Claude have launched one… Claude had launched one model.
Sunny: I think one or two months back, that was a Fable, correct? Clawed Fable. So they were saying this is, like, very advanced model, research-oriented model.
Sunny: Right? So to… and to counter that model, right? So in the, like, in front of that model, basically, they have, this, GPT have launched the Astra.
Sunny: Okay. So, see, model is having a capability we cannot deny with this thing.
Sunny: model can do the coding, it can understand the coding, it can make changes over there. Got it? If you are using this model via OpenAI API, then yeah, it will provide a better reasoning capability in any of other… any of… in any of our tasks, right? But still, everything we cannot leave to the
Sunny: Model, or to the agent right now.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Automate… automation is there, AI automation is there, AI application is also there, cloud is also being used in the industry.
Sunny: Right? But still, we cannot leave everything to the agents, to the system, to the models.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: One example, I'm working in one of the projects, one of the real projects, right?
Sunny: Earlier, they were using the Claude only.
Sunny: Right? So, they have some documentation, their legal document. They are… they need to verify those documents after a certain process. So, earlier, that work was being done by the human. Now, they wanted to know… now they wanted to, like, now they want it to be done by the EI itself, so they have some rules.
Sunny: checks. Based on that, they are reviewing with the AI system. So, they have written the very good cloud skills and all, they were using it very comfortably, but eventually the data, like, become very huge.
Sunny: Okay, in one system, there was, like, 1,000 to 2,000 documents, something like that. So, they asked to the team, okay, can you, can you… to the AI team, basically, can you build a system for us?
Sunny: Can you build the AI system for us? Okay.
Sunny: For sure, we are using the cloud side by side, but yeah, can you build some robust AI system for us, some customized system, where you can give a better UI, we can just put the system ID with respect that we can fetch the document, and AI can review those documents, and AI can review the beautiful result and all. So yeah, so that's a custom AI application.
Sunny: Cloud is still able to do that thing, Cloud SQL is able to do that thing, right? But we can create our own custom application. So that kind of application, enterprises want.
Sunny: Okay? And there, the AI engineer developer is still required. So, whatever model an agent is coming right now, this year, next year, up to next 3 to 5 year, right? So, that cannot replace the teamwork, the human touch, okay, the human intervention.
Sunny: For sure, they can provide some extra intelligence.
Sunny: But, again, that human capability will still be required, what I have seen. Got it?
Sandeep Saboo: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah.
Sandeep Saboo: And, as far as, you know, these things are concerned related to the cost impact, right? So, since I'm actually doing a program management, and then, you know, trying to be more hands-on, with AI, right, so I don't lose the touch.
Sandeep Saboo: So, what I'm seeing is, right now, the cost of the memory and other infra…
Sandeep Saboo: which runs the AI is increasing by many points, right? And there is a tremendous stress on the resources, natural resources, and prices are going up every day. So even the…
Sandeep Saboo: free models, I mean, the LLMs, like OpenAI and Claude, they will have to increase the prices, correct?
Sandeep Saboo: 10.
Sandeep Saboo: Initially, which was, like, a cost motto, that you don't have to hire the people, but rather you use the models to reduce your costs. Now, they are becoming costlier than the human capital.
Sandeep Saboo: Correct. So…
Sandeep Saboo: I mean, it's a… from the program management perspective, I feel like, you know, it's a risk that, you know, we are anyways giving everything to the AI, and then you don't even have any control, and the cost… the primary motto of adopting AI was the cost factor, and the.
Sunny: Hmm.
Sandeep Saboo: speed. So, which is losing out? Because your cost is anyways increasing on a daily basis, if you see the inflation numbers, and XYZ, right?
Sandeep Saboo: Is it really worth it to remove the, I mean, the amount of people getting laid off in the.
Sunny: Okay.
Sandeep Saboo: So, something that, you know, you're seeing in the market, like, companies are realizing this fact that AI is not really cost-worthy, in every case.
Sandeep Saboo: And do you see hirings are going up, or still the layoffs will continue to happen?
Sunny: It… it depends, sir, company to company.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: AI ka cost bad rahe, definitely mahlah, uskele BARDA infrastructure chahiya, GPUs chai, run kar nik liae, hal.
Sunny: companies ko apne, like, employees biore bhane padenge ho jo infrastructure kum manage kar sakteho.
Sunny: Ap dhrid job roles ne program manager hai, product manager hothe hai.
Sunny: Right? Or, people manager jo hot hain. Unka kaam jaatar program kum manage karna hotay.
Sunny: Toh, abih venu kya di kainaki ko log, people are using the AI tools.
Sunny: Or making their work easier.
Sunny: But they are not leaving everything up to the AI. Abih may me recent 2-3 year mah tokoi changes dahiya, Bh s dahiya, ki jolk pallah tola Mehul kam karti, abih auth use kirti tola structure work kan nilag hain. Akhat ja sa koi report, srh dhwik mein banti thi.
Sunny: And, Thabih AIK helps say, within, like, 1 hour or…
Sunny: Tu army banjati hai wo sab chijay. Apoi program manager hota, koi product manager hotathko Vijay ko showcase karna hai, bijan se kusk bachit karne hai, okay, kush documentation banana hai, aapne team ko brief, tobo, chijay bhut fast current.
Sunny: I know. So, that is…
Sunny: AI ka used to BARDA hai Wase platform bhi mahlab abih Redimate platform bhi anilage ay wali.
Sunny: jo ko, Mehi na hua nahiya integration kabih integration, ja seki kuchase hunge joki apne ab, data lekhe ossek reports, intervention human kaur.
Sunny: human Kaos application meh human vinesh ke bicha Bhit pot kajay. Hana. Ak rule mahek hai, ko bhkar rollah bhot cut down othajara hai. Developer sothe thee.
Sunny: BA zute, or bhjanj Team Rate theme Mehli. Okay. Toh, abih BA karuto cut down ho, majesh project maham kar rah hiring in BAK. Bharo, tumi requirement sa matte keh.
Sunny: Or AIC helps usko interpret karke aapna, to mah usko implement kar rah. Toh ye toho ik naya rollah rajde ki bolte hain woke a hai, bohito senior architect kerke roll hai, aur joh pad hai A business sebi Bhat kar sakte hain aap user ka requirement sama sakte hai.
Sunny: karigih companies, aur wo karcha ina wo bh reoccurring na yoga, maybe bhur cost-effective hojaange jake, yaun ka one-time investment ho.
Sunny: jo human resources kohair kirti hain. Toh, ja se, abhi ota hai.
Sunny: requirement aaya, Nay low ko hierarchya, Nayak project aaya. Toh iste china ikbar me aika infrastructure banal lo bhai.
Sunny: Toho long run mahalaya path das bh saif log dahkti mah business waale mahap companies. Toh, de kumato ye baluna, ki program manager y abih to ker replacement nahiya Abhi toh project minkan need hai.
Sunny: With the AI unka kaam o jada structure oya, o jada fataphatarike seh stress full stress Pillai kaam utta akhusi menu karne partiti aap to wo AIGara se hojara.
Sunny: Gir rah board kobi update kar sakte hain. Abhj share pointer internal databases hold the companies kyas ko cha hotai, ya, vinesh mahatab…
Sunny: chatta ki am direct ke bh chatta hai sarh sidhamm development team se baat kar hain wo kudi apna saha requirement balak dahi sakne program manager ke jarva Pari Aange jake, kudase platform rajah, na? Toh ye chi ho sakti hai. So, keep this thing in our mind ki ha, AIC related, ya advanced mahi ye saap chi jaik sakhtun ke kar layout bh sakte hain. Anna? Aga aapi nahiya, lekin, future meh hosta hai api company mahi niura lekin.
Sunny: Kesrie company Challra year, already. For a year, ana?
Sunny: So, yash biapkah dahan me rakna hai. Got it?
Sandeep Saboo: Also, is my emerging pair For forward deployed engineers yay ragh type kar roll raghurs.
Sunny: Abhi toko, forward deployment engineer abih bi hai. Koi forward deployment engineer koi isa koi specific role nahiya. Jaik senior architect, lead tech architect, koi forward deployment engineer hai.
Sunny: Toko ek bhanda Pura kah si project meh saif company meh.
Sunny: Forward deployment jena ko bolta, bhai kar leg hai implement kar leg hai Picher. Bhik bhak ketanag kamkar leg habathum.
Sunny: Meh aapko project, Pur rahe project aki kam dun mein aapi ko develop karna hai, api ko test kar hai, Api ko business bhat karna hai possible hai, kesi project mein.
Sunny: Without Team Kumari usatayin.
Sunny: Pawar deployment engineer kuch nahiya, o serip ek bhanda hai, jukit usko tech kar knowledge hai, already log hai kaam kar rahce tech knowledge logo, AI ka knowledge bhai, or by that time throh experience jojatay Agarw business ko domain kuch samasah bhi effectively BHAT ker sakta hai.
Sunny: Was project kujalice implement kara sekta, production mahal sekta, way forward deployment engineer.
Sunny: Lok hain, sa kam kar raha. Tohrhi. Toh, usko justhur sa modify kar keh dahiya forward deployment engineer, ki bahiya aaphaha use kar raj, fast kari k se kar rah. Thir toh, sah nahiya, ki forward deployment engineer yay wo abhi bhwag hain. Kesu dusran namse war roll hai.
Sunny: karhi nahi sakta hai. No one can do that.
Sunny: Right? Let's say if,
Sunny: basically, there is a person, right? If the person wanted to develop something, wanted to test something, wanted to talk with a business, right?
Sunny: No, nothing, it's impossible.
Sunny: Okay? So, yeah, that skill is fine. With the experience… by the… with the experience, that skills comes up, that FD skill or something like that, right? But yeah, eventually we cannot learn that
Sunny: And,
Sunny: That is not possible. So, aapko kasigna hai, what you have to be learned? You have to be learning how to use AI effectively.
Sunny: Okay? Basically, how to, if you are into the program management side, na, what all tools are there with that? Basically, I can do the quickly automation and all, okay? So, those things you have to be learned. Or, if you wanted to come into the development side, AI engineering side, then…
Sunny: do some good project, learn, like, with me, okay? And then, basically, you can go into that role also. Understood?
Sandeep Saboo: A toda hands-onge mahi courts join gyata, actually, Kavitha on the senior architect plus system design side mahi, zada scope, like a domain plus system design side me.
Sandeep Saboo: Rather than on the management side. So, that's the purpose scheme, and maybe…
Sunny: You are right, your analysis is correct.
Rajib Saha: -Oh.
Sandeep Saboo: Aurk sispush ni dahi akri, ki ye jo abih ola mahai odo Deepika kirti aur apto koi open source model heavy ni, ki busko Pesak harjk karna hobi nh rahit na companies keh mein.
Sandeep Saboo: So, you see, gee open source models will go away, Sirf NVIDIA, he usko Zindar rajattah aki, he has the money right now.
Sandeep Saboo: Just an emo Toronto, yeah, right.
Sunny: Definitely, the bigger company can do that, even NVIDIA has acquired this Hugging Face also recently.
Sandeep Saboo: huh?
Sandeep Saboo: gee water to… I think… they also feel threatened with the OpenAI, I mean, these, these things, NAIDU.
Sunny: They wanted to be expanded on the different side, actually, they have that capability, so definitely they'll invest and acquire some… this kind of firm, right? Nvidia and all, this Hugging Face and all, right?
Sandeep Saboo: Hmm, like.
Sunny: They have a variety of model and all, everything, actually, like…
Sandeep Saboo: open source, you almost close your leg. Sustain ni opange.
Sunny: No, it's not like that, whatever model is coming in the market. See, all the good models are not open source, which we already know, correct?
Sunny: OpenAir and all, right? So, whatever research model is coming, or whatever is… work is being done by the community, right? So that will still be for the community. Maybe NVIDIA will take this thing in another way. They will not close source everything. Got it?
Sandeep Saboo: It's not even supporting…
Sunny: Just check it with the, like, with this LLM benchmark and all, right? You will get which models are good, right?
Sandeep Saboo: Okay.
Sunny: Yup.
Sandeep Saboo: Yeah, thank you, Sunny, and
Rahul: I'm doing it.
Sandeep Saboo: one thing, because today is a teacher's Day, even though I'm, you know, age-wise more.
Sandeep Saboo: But, I really like the way you teach of your Chandra, or even before, you know, you sense the pulse of the listener.
Sandeep Saboo: Qui… So, that requires explanation, or…
Sandeep Saboo: You know, jo, end user raja hum logo, toh, humlogo Bhart me some jahahi usko, because we get overwhelmed, right?
Sunny: So…
Sandeep Saboo: I really appreciate ki aapi… and it's not an easy job, actually, I would say. Kothi preparation karnipathi hogi apku, even though coffees are a session salary type kirti, it's really commendable, I don't know. Because I believe you're not running just this batch, maybe running others and also working full-time.
Sandeep Saboo: So…
Sunny: Yeah, definitely, it takes effort, it takes weekends and all.
Sunny: So, sitting in a weekend also from morning, so that's not an easy thing at all.
Sandeep Saboo: I don't know if you've socialized or not, but it really feels like, Completely block time, basically.
Sunny: Yeah, but yeah, I have… we have that habit, actually, so we… I'm teaching since a long time, it's more than, like, 5 years, so I know, like, how to prepare the material in a shorter period of time, and all that… that's… that basically we can manage, but yeah, like, sometimes there's a time constraint, actually, yeah.
Sandeep Saboo: Yeah, yeah. Truly appreciated, Matlab. Jitna, Tari for Mihir, and thank you.
Sunny: Thank you, sir, thank you very much. Yeah.
Rahul: Hi, Sunny.
Sunny: Yeah, next doubt is just…
Rahul: Rose.
Sunny: Sofia… Sofia is there. Sofia, please go ahead, then Rahul, you can go, okay?
sofia dahiya: Hi, Sunny. Yeah. So, actually, I have a question about the roadmap. I just, I was going through this course, actually. I got access to all the courses for one year. I took that subscription.
sofia dahiya: And I have completed Anitan and the modern route, a no-code route by.
Sunny: My uncle.
sofia dahiya: And I just want to understand, like, if I have to go technically more into depth, I am a data analyst,
sofia dahiya: like, what should be the roadmap I should follow? I'm sorry, this question is not about… particularly about this course. I just want to understand the roadmap. I have sent messages at different… and emails at different platforms.
sofia dahiya: But I haven't received any response, neither from Krish or Mayank or anybody else.
sofia dahiya: So, I was just wondering, and I thought of, you know, asking you, because I was considering this full-stack generative AI bootcamp, or then there is Agentic AI 3.0 by Mayank, and then next AI Forward Deployed Engineer Bootcamp is also coming.
sofia dahiya: So, I just want to understand, like, how should I go about it? Because there are definitely so many courses.
sofia dahiya: And I have to have some roadmap, rather than just, you know, going to one course and the other.
sofia dahiya: Help me understand that.
Sunny: So, what, you wanted… what you wanted to become means, as… as a data analyst, I wanted to be searched as a AI engineer? Or,
sofia dahiya: So, yeah, because I have one…
Sunny: analytes only.
sofia dahiya: note in data analytics, I have started taking projects, in, Anitan for, you know, AI consulting, so…
sofia dahiya: So it is basically, taking a role as a consultant, AI consultant, helping people or businesses, to,
sofia dahiya: So, I'm basically using Ann, or Claude or any other.
sofia dahiya: I want to, you know, work on that, you know?
sofia dahiya: So, working on the workflows, using AI, that's what I want to do. So, basically, that would be a role of, you know, AI consult… consultant, kind of.
sofia dahiya: I just don't want to stay in data analytics.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, okay, got it. So, see, there is two things. The one basically to using an AI, okay? And the another one, basically, to building an AI.
Sunny: Now, if we are building an AI now, that is, again, in a two-way. The first, basically, to utilize some tool, no-code kind of tool, and build the, like, workflows and all, the automated workflow. The other one, basically, it's a full-fledged development. Got it?
sofia dahiya: Yeah.
Sunny: Whatever AI consultants you are doing, the project, basically, you're getting, you're getting more towards the no-code tools at all, correct?
sofia dahiya: Sounds.
Sunny: Claude, cloud, cloud-related, like, the services, like cloud skills code, okay, and the other will basically Nitin, or some other kind of tool. So, see, if…
Sunny: you are, basically aiming to work with these no-code tools, this cloud and cloud more and more, right?
sofia dahiya: Mmm.
Sunny: Basically, you can master this no-code, stuff. There, basically, you will get a more understanding of the AI application, the built-in AI application, and how to utilize that.
Sunny: getting my point, right? So, Agentic Flow is not Nitin and all. Agentic Flow, or this, conversational system, or this Rakesh system, or with this, Claude itself, Claude skills and all, because it is also providing you, like, everything. Claude is also providing the complete ecosystem.
Sunny: Even it is, even the certification is also available of the cloud, right? Cloud Solution Architect, Cloud Developers, cloud professionals, right?
Sunny: So even I have done the Cloud Developer Certificate, and in that, like, so many, like, things related to the Agentic and all, which we can do directly via cloud itself.
Sunny: So, if you want the ready-made tool, okay, on top of that, you wanted to learn… learn those tools, and learn those tools, and you wanted to apply some customization, and you wanted to build the application, then yeah, AI no-code is a good one. You can deep dive over there, into that syllabus. Got it?
Sunny: But if you wanted to become a developer, basically, developer means what? Whoever is doing a… whoever is going to be building a custom application, right? Whoever is basically doing the real AI engineering, whoever is basically deploying that system for the companies, right? So, for the.
sofia dahiya: of…
Sunny: for that, basically, this modern route, okay, AI forward deployment engineer, and the other, basically, batches like, AI Agentic, which Mayank is taking, one of the batches, right? The specialization batch, so those kind of batches require, where the actual development comes to take any framework.
Sunny: from scratch, and build the application. The example which I've given to the previous person, you know, so, one in my, company itself, so they were using the cloud skills, right? So, with that, basically, they will identify, or they will review the data, but again, they want some customized application with some custom functionality, and also, they have… the AI team, the AI development team, or the complete software development team have built
Sunny: application.
Sunny: Right? The UI engineer was there, SD was there, cloud manager was there, right?
sofia dahiya: architect.
Sunny: was there, and then the AI engineers were there. The complete development team was there. So yeah, if you wanted to be into that kind of, basically, role, then this course is perfect. So what I would suggest to you, see, learn both things.
Sunny: understand, this cloud, NATN and all, how to utilize that quickly, okay? And alongside, just to be master this development also. So, wherever you are getting project going forward.
Sunny: whether in no-code, low-code, or whether it's, like, full-fledged development, both you can do. Got it? So just build that capability, because that is required right now, because you even don't know. Let's say today you're getting this project, maybe tomorrow you're not getting that, then what you will do? Again, you will start learning.
Sunny: Right? So that's not a right thing, right choice. So what I'll do, I'd suggest you learn both things, master the no-code as well, the entire cloud ecosystem, whatever tool is in the market right now, and adapt it by the enterprise's company, and, like, develop your development skills also. Got it?
sofia dahiya: Yeah, okay, that helps. So, yeah, I have got good understanding of Claude and Anitan, and I have, like, created many workflows using these tools. So, I'm quite now confident and quite good at that now, I can say.
sofia dahiya: So, yeah, so, yeah, that was the thing, because I also felt like, technically, I should be more strong, you know, now.
sofia dahiya: And so, should I go for, then, Agentic AI 3D that Mayank is teaching, or should I go…
Sunny: You can, see, ma'am, see, actually, if you're, like, attending as much as courses, classes, and all, that won't help you at the end, right? So, first, what I would suggest to you now.
Sunny: Make a proper role map.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: do one thing at a time. Let's see if you're doing this course, complete it.
Sunny: Then later on, you can move to that one, that course.
Sunny: the specialization one, the AI agent, like, where more visibility of the different framework, the more different use cases. Got it? Because at the end, everything is an agent. Now, let's say I'm teaching agent, there is also agent. Got it?
Sunny: Now, what extra you have learned? What extra, basically, you know. You will know, you will learn, basically, whatever you can do by yourself. Let's say, after learning this concept, you are able to build some projects, so that's your real learning, actually. Not that whatever code I have given you, you are just executing it, whether it's an end-to-end project or notebook.
Sunny: Getting my point. Until you don't develop something by your end, then you cannot learn. So what I would suggest to you, make a proper roadmap. If you're completing this, or, like, course, okay? Complete it, let it be finished, do some good project, build one or two good projects from your end.
Sunny: And then, you can learn from that course also later on, means after 2 to 3 months.
Sunny: Okay, if you have capability parallel, you want to do that, you can do that. But don't be, like, too much into the courses and, like, if you are just attending the classes and all, when you will do the self-study, tell me.
Sunny: Right?
sofia dahiya: Right.
Sunny: Understood now. So, take one course, finish that, take at least 80 to 85, 90% learning from that course, and then move to the another one. Got it?
sofia dahiya: Yeah, okay.
Sunny: Go.
sofia dahiya: Yeah, thank you, that helps.
Sunny: Yeah, thank.
Rajib Saha: As a neat.
Sunny: Yeah, Rahul, please go ahead. Rahul, you are there, right?
Sunny: Okay, Rajesh, you can go ahead.
Rajib Saha: Yeah, Sunny, happy Tuesday.
Sunny: Yeah. Yeah, thank you, Rajiv. Thank you very much.
Rajib Saha: Yeah, actually, I want to tell you that I'm getting some problem.
Rajib Saha: Actually, I am teaching interview.
Rajib Saha: And I, everywhere I getting that,
Rajib Saha: Hardcore, need… they need the hardcore coding.
Rajib Saha: Or line by line.
Rajib Saha: I… some days ago, ago, I used, I paid the interview, UTS, UTS, you heard that company name.
Rajib Saha: Yeah, they are asking… they give me, first round interview I completed, and after second round, they, told me
Rajib Saha: They give some, line of code from the project.
Rajib Saha: And, asking me that, where is the, where is the error?
Rajib Saha: Then I, told her that one lady, guys, taking my interview.
Rajib Saha: I told that I can run this code, but, you know, I don't run the code, and actually go line by line, and
Rajib Saha: Tell me where is the issue, and where is the problem, or where I need to change.
Rajib Saha: That type question facing, one… one is question is that, and another question is…
Rajib Saha: Are you getting a, a…
Rajib Saha: facing a problem that when, some, guys asking, that is another company, the Persistent, do you have that?
Rajib Saha: the persisted… the… there is a… I… AI round is completed, I, yeah, my second time, I… because the panel are there, they ask, asking me that
Rajib Saha: Some little question. And, some, one is question is that, about the threading. They told me the… do you know the threading? Yes, I told… I told… that, yes, I, I know.
Rajib Saha: And they're asking that, what is the risk condition. I told him that
Rajib Saha: this condition in that situation, the higher that two functions is, facing, same, same data, they are searching same, same data. Suppose one is.
Rajib Saha: updated, and second, thread is not getting the answer. So, that is the… there is the issue, and they, create the config. I give an example. Suppose I have a, ticket booking system, and there is a, there is a
Rajib Saha: one ticket is there, the two guys are fighting for the one ticket. Then that situation is the race condition is happening.
Rajib Saha: And… Then, they told me that, can you write the code for it?
Rajib Saha: I told yes, I started to run, and sometime I forget the acquire and the release section, and I also, create the where we need to start, and where the function is start, and create call, and object create call, and after the target, and the function name, all of this I clear.
Rajib Saha: But I forget to, actually, I did this work a long time ago, so I can't remember that… the… what is the acquire, and what is the release, I will call. Actually, time, I forget it.
Rajib Saha: So they decide that I can't do anything, say, close the, interview.
Rajib Saha: That type of facing the… actually, they are asking, the, machine test, and they are… I am facing that type of, issue for the, attending the interview.
Rajib Saha: And I, one guy told, that, it is a smart time, and where if I need, then I go to the chat GPT, there get any issue, or I get any problem, then I, take the helping chat, and also I, show one project that I can be… I can build that type of, RAG application, I show.
Rajib Saha: the guys. But they, need the hardcore, coding.
Rajib Saha: I don't understand that in those situations, nowadays, we are facing the smart developer, and we are, taking the cloud help, Chad GBT help.
Rajib Saha: If I face any problem or face any issue, then I take the help. If I get an error, then I paste the error to the chat and get the solution every… where I'm working, that type of, development.
Rajib Saha: So, in that situation, why they asking that type of question, I don't know. And what is the interview session is going in those days? Can you tell me that,
Rajib Saha: how I take my preparation, and I need the code, code, code, line-by-line coding for the interview. I have, I need to take this type of situ… preparation.
Sunny: It's, sir, completely dependent on the interviewer, okay?
Sunny: we don't know, like, what they might ask, right? If they are in a mood to ask the line-by-line code, maybe they felt they should ask to you.
Sunny: Right? Or maybe they want some reason to reject some person, so they can ask this kind of question, actually.
Sunny: Got it.
Sunny: Right? So… so, actually, I… even… we cannot predict… I… even I cannot say, like, where they will ask the line-by-like coding, or that kind of question, where, like, we generally don't practice before the interviews and all.
Rajib Saha: Right?
Sunny: So, first of all, you will have to be, like, understand for what kind of company, for which company you're giving an interview, right? You will have to check their interview history, what they ask. You can simply search over the Chad GPT or over the internet, right?
Sunny: how many rounds they are taking, you can even look into some YouTube videos also, if someone has already given their interview and all. Got it.
Rajib Saha: So, with that.
Sunny: you can get some idea. Now, there is one assurity. If you're giving an interview for TireOne company, let's say Google, Amazon, Flipkart, Walmart, okay.
Sunny: or Intuit, or for any other big company, right, the big product giant like OpenAir, Anthropic, okay, Netflix. So, they will definitely ask the, this coding question.
Sunny: For those companies will have to be prepared. But the other company, let's say, for any big four, for any other domain-specific company, right? For, let's say, persistence, for any other consulting, right? If you're giving interview, generally they don't ask these kind of questions in the interview. Then, yeah, we are not preparing many times, correct? We are not…
Sunny: Doing the line-by-line coding preparation and all, okay? But, again, sir, it completely depends on the interviewer, okay? So, keep generic your preparation.
Sunny: I'll learn according to the job description, and be ready with your AI concept and all, and the project in all.
Sunny: If anyone is asking plan byline code and all, then you can even… even… even you can counter to those interviewers, okay? So, I know that, I can do it, but right now I'm not able to remember this thing.
Sunny: Okay, generally I'm taking help of the co-pilot, you can even mention that.
Sunny: Okay, because, like, we have to be, like, complete our code and all everything in a faster manner, but yeah, I'm good in a debugging, I can still do that, solve that. So, some understanding you should also have, actually, right, of the coding.
Sunny: Okay, explicitly, you can mention to that interviewer. If they… they will… they need to be under… they will understand definitely, right? But again, intentionally they are doing this thing, then we cannot do anything. Got it.
Rajib Saha: Actually, actually, I, focus that I know clearly there is a… if we, open one vacancy, there is…
Rajib Saha: applied, more than one, 100, 200, 400, the type of, candidates are applying for this, for this post. So, I think that there, there is the, opportunity, the, empire that rejected the guys and, did not take the proper interview.
Rajib Saha: Bye.
Rajib Saha: it… there is a… maybe the cause, I think. It may be…
Sunny: So, do one thing. So, see if you're getting this kind of experience, if someone is asking you the… so just prepare something, right?
Rajib Saha: for your name.
Sunny: Next interview, prepare some line-by-line stuff or some coding-related things.
Rajib Saha: A lot of things are there. They are asking for python, they are asking from pythonic, they are asking for First API, they are asking from a lot of, everything or everything, how everyone can remember all of the code line balance. That is the.
Sunny: See, sir, it's not about the remembering, sir. See…
Rajib Saha: if someone.
Sunny: Someone really works onto this concept now, they no need to be remember all this thing.
Sunny: Got it. First of all, tell me in which technology you have experienced?
Sunny: Tell me.
Rajib Saha: Yeah, actually, I'm, searching a job full-stack development, as well as the.
Sunny: No, no, no, no. Right now, what… where you are working, how much experience you have?
Rajib Saha: Yeah, actually, I'm working in Python now.
Rajib Saha: the jungle.
Sunny: No, you are working in Python.
Rajib Saha: Yeah, I turned yang.
Rajib Saha: Then, finally…
Sunny: Django, if you are working in that, I think, see, you should not be, like, this worry about the code and all, right? So…
Rajib Saha: Yeah. Spotify will be very easy.
Sunny: for you, correct?
Rajib Saha: Yeah, actually, I have the confidence
Rajib Saha: That I can, do that type of every, type of, development I can do, or, I can deliver the, project. Actually, I did this job.
Rajib Saha: But I… a lot of time, every time it is not possible to write the line-by-line code or explain the line-by-line code.
Rajib Saha: Every time I did not write, in the, for the project, I can take the…
Sunny: I can say, if you are getting this kind of question and this kind of explanation, just whatever code you write, just understand that line by line, okay? Or just…
Sunny: Just, like, try to be… try to convince to the interviewer also, okay.
Rajib Saha: Mugg.
Sunny: say that I… I know this one, but I forget, something like that, okay?
Rajib Saha: This would work.
Sunny: Auto.
Rajib Saha: Okay, okay, Sunny. Actually, I am facing this problem, so I think… I think that I discussed with you, so if there I can get any solution, thank you for it. You guide me.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, sir, thank you.
piyush_kumar: Hi, Lieuten.
Rahul Kumar: Hi, it's Anand.
Rahul Kumar: Your next…
Sunny: status. Push, SUNIL, anyone is there, please go.
sunil: Yeah, I think I was…
Rahul Kumar: too.
Sunny: Yeah, Rahul Rahul, let's go ahead. You go first.
Rahul Kumar: Yeah.
Rahul Kumar: Cheer.
Rahul Kumar: Actually, I just wanted to know about the React that… the React concept has been completed, right? React agent?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, we understand that, no? In the previous class.
Rahul Kumar: So, can you please show me the code? Actually, I went… I go through the code, so I am not able to figure it out. I just done the kind of things, and the structure tools and tool…
Rahul Kumar: It is there, not just…
Sunny: Just check with the GitHub, you will get this code, right? So… Just a sec.
Rahul Kumar: This is the same thing, na, where we are, you know…
Rahul Kumar: by the LLM, calling the tools, right?
Sunny: Just check out with this class, this one, okay?
Rahul Kumar: Okay.
Rahul Kumar: Okay, and also, I have a similar question, like what Sandeep said.
Rahul Kumar: Actually, I am working as an engineering manager, and basically doing programming as well. So I have experience of 15 plus in Shikha.
Rahul Kumar: So, due to this AI kind of thing, I just took this course to transit myself in AI stability, so that we can
Rahul Kumar: implement.
Rahul Kumar: these Agentic pipelines in our C Sharp applications.
Rahul Kumar: Okay, so this is the correct path, right?
Sunny: Yes, definitely. You are into the right path.
Sunny: So, if you're able to complete, this thing, this course.
Sunny: Along with the projects and all, then you can transition yourself, okay?
Rahul Kumar: Okay, so,
Rahul Kumar: Also, there is… I am getting some calls as well, related to FDA. So, what I can think of, this is the same role that we are already doing, we are already developed.
Rahul Kumar: Deploying the things, we are already creating the things, we are already coordinating with business. So they have changed the terminology, term in the field of AI, right?
Sunny: Yeah, actually, that is, like, more practical, or more development side. SD-related thing is also there, cloud-specific thing is also there. Okay, the project mindset, the delivery mindset would be there, so that is all about the MD.
Sunny: Now, this, basically, it is, like, develop… along with the development, the AI development side, with the fundamental of the generative AI.
Sunny: So that is what we are covering over here, got it?
Rahul Kumar: Okay, and the related… for the last discussion, the person who is telling na, the…
Rahul Kumar: interviewer is asking for the programming question, is asking to write the questions, right? If technical person is taking your interview now.
Rahul Kumar: So everyone knows that theoretical stuff. So…
Rahul Kumar: To know whether the… The person is able to understand what he is able to write.
Rahul Kumar: Is the primary agenda to know whether the other person is able Able to write the code.
Rahul Kumar: This is the primary agenda to check.
Rahul Kumar: the person. Also, it depends on the way, as you said, in which company you are going. So, in our company, I… we always ask.
Rahul Kumar: Two or three questions.
Rahul Kumar: To the programmers to write something.
Rahul Kumar: So that is…
Rahul Kumar: In the market, it is still required. In the R system, which is our system, it will be company, for the project manager interview, they are also
Rahul Kumar: Asking these kind of questions.
Rahul Kumar: You need to prepare on that part as well.
Sunny: Yeah, great, great.
Rahul Kumar: Yeah.
Sunny: Thank you, thank you for the input, thank you.
piyush_kumar: Hi, Sinzo.
sunil: Hello, Sanjay Nayak.
Sunny: Yeah, Piers, you can go ahead. Then, Sunil, you can go.
piyush_kumar: So, first of all, sir, happy Teacher's Day, and… Thank you.
Sunny: Thank you very much, Piush. Thank you.
piyush_kumar: So, actually, mujay, Kanata ki…
piyush_kumar: Krishna Kush das mahra distracted Chandra course. Agi gee chijay Pani lag gyaung. Memory hogya, evaluation hogya, and
piyush_kumar: observation hogya, ease of topics.
piyush_kumar: Toh, to ragh se… topics ab meh agar kuchh bi Pani jara utahi mujhe thinking bohot jada Challa jara usme ki mudle production kirti banana, wah toher.
piyush_kumar: Arya.
piyush_kumar: Project spanana rajan unto, like, fir bohapi, jise abhi meh Ajit wale part mein mahi complete Kodaliya, bhap das ki aap mujihapne backend skuk anakarna AIC loop se, basically, agent orchestration seh. Toh fir boh may problem hudi mujheara hectic rajara Mehlei, aur mu seh hoi ni rajekj.
piyush_kumar: leiya.
Sunny: Okay, so, Deepika, what I will suggest you now? Abhi thwa do Purani chijay hain legacy wali CHU un pythna focus nahi karoo.
Sunny: Got it.
Sunny: RAG, Agentic AI.
Sunny: Uske Bad, MCP, guardrails, evaluation, isara cha sum jo.
Sunny: Cloud wala part sum jojek. Okay, and then Usput projects Bharan.
Sunny: Got it.
piyush_kumar: multimodal, like, Azure bala tha.
piyush_kumar: And toher woale projecta, toh uma pe toh sab se paan lei mahap credit card y Mahangiliya, account open kar nik wala. Toh sara uskeleena fir mahi aisk alternative Dunda, ki mujay video download kerna tanak lia, basically, usme Ada. If YouTube ke ling ko, dahiy.
Sunny: Abhi college mehoka.
piyush_kumar: So we're finally at it.
Sunny: cloud ki knowledge hona, different thing, cloud implementation kar naik, different chid ya, na? So, aber Mahalo student oya johi ho, student wealth si ID, balk, sorry, cloud ko access ker satio ab AWS Google DONOPEC credit multine student ko.
Sunny: So, practice kar sakteo easily, right? Kushi Yadav k ki… strategy, follow KUM.
piyush_kumar: profile check yatha. Mano ka profile check kiata, woke profile kanun githap ni dalai, uneas explanation video jaal ragh ke hai. So, mujhe vai kan deployment tohm seh hota nih hai.
Sunny: Definitely. Aapko deployment nikan, aapk knowledge hona cheech ka.
Sunny: Right? After knowledge hai to project be deploy ki hai sua self practice ki it is fine. Fresh aroh, itna ja metar nik karta, agar college.
piyush_kumar: It's fantastic.
Sunny: Koi bh roll pet degignation hai job to Challa dahiya, bhika.
piyush_kumar: Saha placement, like, KAL campus y tray kart na padega.
Sunny: aur jetny preparation ki hai, AI balay is mainly part pe focus ko ja meh batahya us branch peh, MLD utan dsare basic, basic concept samoj losapke. That's it, ki?
piyush_kumar: And, sir, like, mano kud banaya ta rag pay, toh, screen share Kanig option… So…
Sunny: No, you can share, I can add you in a panelist.
Sunny: Yes, SUNIL, what's your doubt? Meanwhile, you can go ahead with.
sunil: Yeah, I would, actually, I wanted to understand, like, one design. I have one design question.
sunil: So, first of all, yeah, happy Teacher's Day, Sunny.
sunil: Thank you.
Sunny: everybody.
sunil: Please, yeah, you are the only teachers what I have right now.
sunil: Oop.
sunil: So, the design question, actually,
sunil: It's, like, it's a very simple Ajitent, which I'm thinking to build it.
sunil: let's say, you know, there's one… let me give you one example to you. You know, this real estate. If you wanted to book your flight or something, then you book it, and then they… so you are booking based on the way, their quotation.
sunil: And based on the quotation, then if you want to make some changes, you can do that. And then they create an agreement, right? A sales agreement, if you're going forward.
sunil: Then, based on the sales agreement, that big real estate, they have their own ERP system. They create an order also, so that they can…
sunil: fulfill that order through their ERP, and whatever taxation and everything will be taken care of by their ERP itself.
sunil: Now, the… let's say, problem is…
sunil: That agent, if I want to sell to this real estate.
sunil: So, one real estate company might have… are using different type of agreement. Like, their structure is very different.
sunil: And, some other real estate companies have their very different of structures.
sunil: Or their schema is very different.
sunil: So… and my agent will take their input of that agent.
sunil: I mean, they, they're, contract.
sunil: And it will parse it, understand those 20-30 fields, which are very important, like payment terms.
sunil: other conditions, delivery conditions, or penalty, and all those things. It will understand, those things, and then it will update in that content, as well as the order.
sunil: So now, let's say that they can… I know, okay, ERP, I understand many companies are using,
sunil: Oracle and SAP, so I understand their structure, what Boom.
sunil: their ERP structure. But that contract structure will be different. Some are using only, normal document type, some companies are using, contract management applications, like, I certainly use Congra, so…
sunil: these, schema are very different. So I wanted to build That agent, which…
sunil: kind of plug-and-play for any real estate. If I tell it to them, then they just plug their contact system, either it's document or API, and my agents would understand their schema.
sunil: So how should I design that?
sunil: RAG… and RAG, I was thinking, but RAG… Oh…
sunil: would be very costly, because… costly or… or… or that means it takes much effort, because every deal needs then one new document. Then we should do the chunking, ingestion, and the retrieval for each document type.
sunil: So that I am not considering, like, for every deal, there will be a one… every time there will be one, injection, and then retrieval.
sunil: Are there any way where I can have some universal schema, or any real estate, they can use it, irrespective of how they use their structure?
sunil: Not today.
Sunny: Yeah, so see, if you have a company contract sources, right, Let's say, document, or…
Sunny: Whatever, right? DV and all. So you can, build some connector layer on top of that.
Sunny: Okay. And the different, different, basically, layers you can create means the complete data pipeline you can, design first. Got it? That is required for your application.
Sunny: And on top of it, basically, you can implement the Agent TK earlier.
Sunny: Getting my point.
sunil: Data pipeline, can you explain this?
Sunny: Sorry?
sunil: data pipeline.
Sunny: Your data pipeline, have you built that?
sunil: connected. No, see, data pipeline is one thing I was thinking, with POC, which I'm doing, taking data from, like.
sunil: SharePoint.
sunil: So, let's say I know, like, one company, they are using SharePoint, and they store a document type. Like, they have their own PDF, they are storing that. So I… so I know their structure.
sunil: So, then I'm picking from the SharePoint, and using the LLM to parse that, getting those 2035 which I wanted to validate.
sunil: That is, like, working.
sunil: But if I'm going with the big customers, let's say, who are hitting any…
sunil: proper contact management system, like ICRTs. Even they are, they are also having document.
sunil: But their document structure will be different from this customer.
sunil: So… How should I have my connector, what you said, or data pipeline?
sunil: Which understands any of, structure or schema.
sunil: the company A, B, C, D,
sunil: Everyone have very, very different, schema and structures.
Sunny: Sir, do one thing, just send me that… this problem, just somewhere on, like, in a mail or somewhere, okay? Tomorrow.
Sunny: I can give you the answer. Maybe we'll have to be think.
sunil: Sure, sure, sure.
Sunny: Because, see.
sunil: do that.
Sunny: I would not design even RAG system for this one, since your challenge is, like, that every customer contract system has a different schema, correct?
sunil: 2…
Sunny: I want to introduce a connector layer over here.
Sunny: Okay, we can design some dynamic schema also, it is there inside the pythontec and all, everything we can do.
Sunny: Okay, dynamic schema capability is also there, means whatever, like, data you have, according to that, on the way, you can create a schema.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: So that is called the canonical schema. Just search about this term, how to create.
sunil: beginner.
Sunny: the schema.
Sunny: All good.
sunil: Okay, Lucas.
Sunny: Problem statement, I'll check that, okay?
sunil: I will… I won't tell you, because today's session, even I was feeling this patenting would be promising, or somehow it can help.
sunil: Okay, I will, I will read about this dynamic schema and canonical impedentic.
sunil: And as well as I will share with you the problem.
Sunny: Sure, sure.
sunil: Thank you, thank you, Sunny.
Sunny: Thank goodness.
piyush_kumar: Sir, so… library Dewan, and, they say keep kudka chenga kudka loader, basically, and,
piyush_kumar: So, agar asa kar sakte, ki asa package venu jaape muja pura ki hak pipeline na na banana prade barbar aur basiken call karoo, and then beta workar, and then is meh file path do, meh apna loader choose karu, chunker choose karu, and then embedder.
piyush_kumar: and then vector database, and iske BCH mahlab ki meh modules and package files, jo sa har rajesh kar kah run karu, toh mujhe Krishkik nijay koduku tu muji chenga ki ga, muja koi kodi ya.
Sunny: Mmm.
Sunny: Yeah, definitely, you can do that. Actually, we are doing the same thing now, correct?
Sunny: We were create… we were having that, streamlit UI and all. If you remember in our RAC project, right, so everything, we were setting it from one UI, and the entire functionality was the abstract one, so you can create it.
Sunny: Alright.
piyush_kumar: No, actually, are you saying that, sir, asa ik fandsan jo ki mahlah, it sa harbahar ha ma agar Puch banate ragh mein tohame Pura ragh pipe banana bhta haikura proper pipeline. Toh agar mah se, pip me akarh, like, upload Gardo, you say beta ver kannar.
Sunny: Aha! Kurse satio na, aapna package balak upload kart Dhan saifer install kar linea, direct koi bhi kart saktahifer toh.
piyush_kumar: Abhi tak meh mah sip chaqing parta ki use ki ha. BARTM multiple options recursive Thahir semantic, so,
piyush_kumar: So, multiple options.
Sunny: Definitely das. Sara, JoJo's optional chenga would be.
piyush_kumar: Text loader may abhih mahiba, basically, text loader use KAYLA JSON and PDF and all other big karte hain.
piyush_kumar: One more thing, sir, and Mi Naik project, huh?
piyush_kumar: Muted.
piyush_kumar: So, toh mah mahesh ka proper ye design manajesh mein…
piyush_kumar: appointment kirti habi speech pe aate ho, then aapka appointment ka details hota hai. Toh aaph follow-up pe ki kirti o toh, direct hamara intent follow-up ke saath to hamare orchestration, mahat orchestration fee chala ja thai.
piyush_kumar: And then mahapi intent kahat aapka jo ham database aapka appointment details leilete, and then aap keele Agala follow-up theapar neathe, ya, reschedule ke leh, then reschedule ke li.
piyush_kumar: So, iska proper flow… You don't be a…
piyush_kumar: banana kay.
piyush_kumar: rapport.
piyush_kumar: jump.
piyush_kumar: Okay, so ha, toh, appointment booking card toh, yaha payment workflow ko, like, DR query, patient ID, problem, department, and date and time.
piyush_kumar: Agaran karun yehuram, coordinated and safety, then router, then appointment, cancel, follow-up reschedule, then response emergency. Ap mujin aapay, like,
piyush_kumar: Memory layer dahalap kiking ye gh se ki mahatab mere agent ku ya dahi hai patient ke baika Bhathi.
piyush_kumar: Yeah, yeah, definitely.
Sunny: Definitely, yeah, you can do it after the next class, okay?
piyush_kumar: Buh.
piyush_kumar: Okay, thank you. And, sir, like, this is Amari Kurse mein boh sare already working professionals, and Krishk Aadar ravi Bhhari project, mahlib courses meh working professionals hai. Those are, like, internally, raptals balas.
Sunny: Mmm.
piyush_kumar: Better raghookies.
Sunny: Rahul bhagar rajar kyabolte hain, rappro kara.
Sunny: Agar aapko campus placement namel, off-campus, okay? Then I can guide you related to that. Got it?
piyush_kumar: So, Saravaitavne banay eta wo jo, fine-tune karke ek banay eta meh.
piyush_kumar: Agentic aurik fine-tune bala.
piyush_kumar: Saha apply kar namu jeto.
Sunny: Yeah, sure, sure, definitely.
Sunny: Ugh.
Sunny: you can, basically let us know, so just share your resume and all, and I'll share with my team. If any sort of opportunity will be there, they'll let you know, okay? Up front.
piyush_kumar: Thank you, sir. Thank you very much.
Sunny: Inc.
Sunny: Okay, guys, I'll see you in the next class. Thank you, bye-bye, take care. If you have any doubt, you can ask me. Yeah, thank you.